(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-09-17T01:44:09.083322",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.8-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あー！こよりスケッチ！
Ah! Koyori Sketch!
ででーん！
Ta-da!
はい、萌えよ！
Alright, feel the moe!
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
研究室らしい視点転換！
A lab-style perspective shift!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いまどきの視点転換！
A modern perspective shift!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
こよりの助手くん、ワンネーム！
Koyori's Assistant-kun, one name!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわぁ〜！エロボ！
Whoa~! Sexy voice!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわぁ〜！いぼ痔が〜！
Whoa~! My hemorrhoids~!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
頭脳なんでね、見極め！
Since I've got the brains, I'll see right through it!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
かわいいです、ギャ〜ス！
It's so cute, gyaas!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
オッケー！こくよーび！そう！
Okay! Kokuyoubi! That's right!
やったー！間に合っ太朗！
Yay! Made it in the nick of time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a beverage.
ちなみにすだちは空気です
By the way, sudachi is air.
はい、お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes, Big Bro! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですか、助かる！
I always keep frozen udon stocked. Is that so? What a lifesaver!
やったー！証明完了、Q.E.D.！
Yay! Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
コクだろ、コク！ギャース！
It's all about richness, richness! Gyaas!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
首輪には地雷を仕込んでる！
A landmine is rigged in my collar!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
大丈夫かな？うい、うい、うい、うい！
Will it be okay? Oui, oui, oui, oui!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いやーー！効きませんね！
Nooo! That has no effect!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
思い知らそうか！
Shall I teach you a lesson?!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もふもふのプログラムはできた！
The fluffy program is complete!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
はーい、協定！
Alright, pact agreed!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うーー！あーー！
Ooooh! Aaaah!
やったー！間に合っ太朗！
Yay! Made it in the nick of time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a beverage.
ちなみにすだちは空気です
By the way, sudachi is air.
はい、お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes, Big Bro! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですか、助かる！
I always keep frozen udon stocked. Is that so? What a lifesaver!
やったー！私の戦闘力は53万です！
Yay! My battle power is 530,000!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
実は私は、13歳です！
Actually, I'm 13 years old!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
何色が好き？桃色だよ！
What color do you like? Pink!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
たけのこ派ね！すごく好き！
Team Takenoko, right! I love it!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
わーー！153！
Whoa~! 153!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ヤクルトは、飲み物ではありません！
Yakult is not a beverage!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
豚骨ラーメンです！ギャース！
It's tonkotsu ramen! Gyaas!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
しっぽも振っていいのです！
It's fine to wag your tail, too!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
みんなの応援がいつもだよ！見ててーーーー！
Everyone's support is always with me! Keep watching meee!
やったー！間に合っ太朗！
Yay! Made it in the nick of time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a beverage.
ちなみにすだちは空気です
By the way, sudachi is air.
はい、お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes, Big Bro! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですか、助かる！
I always keep frozen udon stocked. Is that so? What a lifesaver!
やったー！せーの、こくよーびよ〜！
Yay! Ready, set, it's Kokuyoubi~!
こくよーびだよ〜！
It's Kokuyoubi~!
せーの、こくよーび！そう！
Ready, set, Kokuyoubi! That's right!
はい、ハッシュタグ！こより実験中でしょう！
Alright, hashtag! It must be #KoyoriJikkenchu!
オッケー！
Okay!
こよは、頭脳です！頭脳派ですか？助かる！
Koyo is the brains! You're on the brainy side? What a lifesaver!
やったー！
Yay!
こよりスケッチ！
Koyori Sketch!
ででーん！
Ta-da!
はい、萌えよ！
Alright, feel the moe!
せーの！
Ready, set, go!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
研究室らしい視点転換！
A lab-style perspective shift!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いまどきの視点転換！
A modern perspective shift!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
こよりの助手くん、ワンネーム！
Koyori's Assistant-kun, one name!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわぁ〜！エロボ！
Whoa~! Sexy voice!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわぁ〜！いぼ痔が〜！
Whoa~! My hemorrhoids~!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
頭脳なんでね、見極め！
Since I've got the brains, I'll see right through it!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
かわいいです、ギャ〜ス！
It's so cute, gyaas!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
オッケー！こくよーび！そう！
Okay! Kokuyoubi! That's right!
やったー！間に合っ太朗！
Yay! Made it in the nick of time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a beverage.
ちなみにすだちは空気です
By the way, sudachi is air.
はい、お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes, Big Bro! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですか、助かる！
I always keep frozen udon stocked. Is that so? What a lifesaver!
やったー！証明完了、Q.E.D.！
Yay! Proof complete, Q.E.D.!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
コクだろ、コク！ギャース！
It's all about richness, richness! Gyaas!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
首輪には地雷を仕込んでる！
A landmine is rigged in my collar!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
大丈夫かな？うい、うい、うい、うい！
Will it be okay? Oui, oui, oui, oui!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
いやーー！効きませんね！
Nooo! That has no effect!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
思い知らそうか！
Shall I teach you a lesson?!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
もふもふのプログラムはできた！
The fluffy program is complete!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
はーい、協定！
Alright, pact agreed!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うーー！あーー！
Ooooh! Aaaah!
やったー！間に合っ太朗！
Yay! Made it in the nick of time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a beverage.
ちなみにすだちは空気です
By the way, sudachi is air.
はい、お兄ちゃん！全開！
Yes, Big Bro! Full throttle!
冷凍うどんは常備してます、そうですか、助かる！
I always keep frozen udon stocked. Is that so? What a lifesaver!
やったー！私の戦闘力は53万です！
Yay! My battle power is 530,000!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
実は私は、13歳です！
Actually, I'm 13 years old!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
何色が好き？桃色だよ！
What color do you like? Pink!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
たけのこ派ね！すごく好き！
Team Takenoko, right! I love it!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
わーー！153！
Whoa~! 153!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
ヤクルトは、飲み物ではありません！
Yakult is not a beverage!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
豚骨ラーメンです！ギャース！
It's tonkotsu ramen! Gyaas!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
しっぽも振っていいのです！
It's fine to wag your tail, too!
はい！はい！はい！はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
みんなの応援がいつもだよ！見ててーーーー！
Everyone's support is always with me! Keep watching meee!
やったー！間に合っ太朗！
Yay! Made it in the nick of time!
マヨネーズは飲み物です
Mayonnaise is a beverage.
ちなみにすだちは空気です
By the way, sudachi is air.
はい！
Alright!
こにちゅ〜！ 助手くん、冷凍うどんは常備してますかー？
Kon-nichu~! Assistant-kuns, do you keep frozen udon stocked at home?
はーい！
Yes!
やったー！ せーの、こんこよ〜！
Yay! Ready, set, Konkoyo~!
博衣こよりだよ〜！
It's Hakui Koyori~!
せーの、こんこよです〜！
Ready, set, Konkoyo-desu~!
はい！ ハッシュタグ「#こよりスケッチ」よろしく〜！
Okay! Please use the hashtag #KoyoriSketch~!
オッケー！
Okay!
今夜はずの... 頭脳派ですかー？
Are you the intellectual type tonight?
はーい！
Yes!
やったー！ こよりスケッチ、デデン！
Yay! Koyori Sketch, ta-da!
はい、ほえ〜！ せーの！
Alright, whoa~! Ready, set!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
研究者らしい助手くん！
Assistant-kun who acts like a researcher!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
未来の助手くん！
Future Assistant-kun!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
有料助手くんは寝る！
Member Assistant-kun goes to sleep!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
うわ〜！ てへぺろ！
Whoa~! Tehepero!
はい！ はい！ はい！ はい！
Hai! Hai! Hai! Hai!
女のがちトーーーク！ 第4回〜〜！
Girls' Real Talk, Episode 4~~!
イエーーイ！ やったーー！
Yay! Woohoo!
4回目だ！
It's the fourth one!
4回...
Fourth...
4回目です！ そして今回もなんと...
It is our fourth! And today, believe it or not...
ゲストがいます！ やったーー！
...we have a guest! Yay!
やったーー！
Yay!
お邪魔してます〜！
Thanks for having me~!
いらっしゃーい！
Welcome!
いらっしゃいませー！
Welcome, welcome!
ということで、いらっしゃいませー！
So, welcome! Today...
本日はノエル先輩が遊びに来てくれました。よろしくお願いいたしますー！
...Noel-senpai has come to join us! Welcome to the show!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please treat me well! / Let's have fun!
ほんなら、ちょっと自己紹介がてら、あの、今日の意気込みなど聞いてみましょうか。
Well then, how about some introductions and hearing everyone's enthusiasm for today?
じゃ、ラミィたん！
First up, Lamy-tan!
はい！
Yes!
ホロライブ5期生の、顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！
From Hololive 5th Gen, "my face is my liver," I'm Yukihana Lamy!
今日もどんな相談が来てるのか楽しみです！ よろしくお願いしまーす！
I'm looking forward to seeing what kind of advice questions we got today! Let's have a great time!
お願いしまーす！
Let's do this!
そして、すのすのの頭脳の方、博衣こよりだよー！
And I'm the brains of Sunosuno, Hakui Koyori~!
えー、毎回どんどんマシュマロが増えている気がします。
I feel like we're getting more and more Marshmallows each time.
おおー！ 嬉しいことだ！
Ooh! That's wonderful!
ねー！ 本当嬉しくって。
Right?! It makes me so happy.
あとはみんなが結構ね、恋愛してるんだなーとホクホクしております！
Plus, it warms my heart knowing so many of you are experiencing romance!
えー、今日もありがとうございます！ よろしくお願いしまーす！
Thank you so much for today as well! Let's have fun!
お願いしまーす！
Let's do this!
そして、ゲストのノエル先輩！ どうですか、この番組？
And now, our guest Noel-senpai! What do you think of this show?
はい！ プレッシャー！
Yes! Talk about pressure!
えー、皆さん、こんまっする〜！ ホロライブ3期生の白銀ノエルです！
Kon-muscle everyone~! I'm Shirogane Noel from Hololive 3rd Gen!
いや、ずっとね、ちょっと興味があり...
Well, I've actually been interested in this for a while...
何だったら、こよちゃんとかにね、その、いや...
In fact, I'd ask Koyo-chan and others like...
『あれってゲスト、どんな感じになってるんですか？』って
"So what's the deal with guests on that show?"
チラッチラッ。『いつでも空いてますよ』みたいなね
Glancing over like, "I'm free anytime, you know."
そういう感じで、ちょっと構ちょムーブをしたら...
After dropping hints that I wanted some attention...
なんと今回お呼びいただきました！ ありがとうございます！
...believe it or not, I got invited! Thank you so much!
ありがとうございます！ 嬉しい！
Thank you! We're so glad!
いや、ほんとにね、この番組、よく言ってるんですけど、とっても人を選ぶと思っておりまして...
Well really, as I often say, this show is definitely an acquired taste, so...
まあね！
Well, yeah!
ま、もちろん存じ上げておりますのでね。
Well, of course I'm well aware of that.
ま、この深い時間にやるのにね、あの、ぴったりな深い番組になってるので...
Well, it's such a deep show that fits this late-night hour perfectly...
行きたいって言ってもらえるのすごい嬉しかったんですけど、今日はよろしくお願いしまーす！
...so hearing that you wanted to come made me so happy! Let's have a great time today!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Looking forward to it!
NGはない感じですかね？
So there are no topics that are off-limits for you?
いや、もちろん！ NGなんてありま……せん！
Of course! Off-limits topics? Absolutely... not!
本当ですか！？
Really?!
間があったよ？
There was a pause there!
ないの！？
None at all?!
ない！ いや、うん、まあ...
None! Well, okay, I mean...
おっ？
Oh?
ちょっとね、皆さんの、なんか恋愛がどんな感じなのかっていうのも...
Well, depending on what everyone's love lives are like...
それ次第なところはあるけど、団長的には、あの、NGないかなって...
...it might depend on that, but personally, I don't think I have any off-limits topics...
おお〜！
Ooh~!
もちろんその、やっぱこのね、番組、団長もちょっと見させていただいておりまして...
Of course, I've been watching this show myself...
あ、ありがとうございます！ 嬉しい！
Ah, thank you! That's so nice!
なんか『団長だったらこんな気持ちだなー』とか、そういうのを想像しながらやってたので...
I'd watch while imagining how I would feel in those situations...
今のところNGは...ええ。
...so as of right now, off-limits topics are... none.
今のとこ、今のとこね！
As of right now, that is!
今のとこね。今日どうだろ...
Right now, yeah. Wonder about today...
今日ちょっとぶっ飛んでたら、ちょっと分かんないかも。
If today gets totally unhinged, I might not be so sure.
今日、ま、今日でも同じぐらいの感じかなと思いますので...
Well, I think today will be around the usual level...
はい！
Okay!
はい、よろしくお願いしま... 答えづらい時はね、あの、『答えづらい』って言ってください、はっきり！
So let's have fun! If anything is hard to answer, just be honest and say "That's hard to answer"!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Let's do this!
正直にね！
Keep it honest, right!
はい！
Yes!
分かりました！
Understood!
はい、無理強いはいたしません！
Yes, no forcing anything!
それでは見ていきたいと思います。じゃ、1個目、ジャブで、これ言っていいですか？
Now then, let's take a look. First, as a jab, can I read this one?
ジャブ？
A jab?
ジャブというか、なんですけど...
Well, sort of a jab, but...
えー、『こよちゃんは「ノエル先輩」呼びですが、団長はもっと打ち解けて愛称呼びしてほしいなーって。
"Koyo-chan calls you Noel-senpai, but does Danchou want her to be more casual and use a nickname?
「マリリン」並みの愛称考えちゃいませんか？』ということで。
How about coming up with a nickname on par with Marilyn?" That's what it says.
おおー！ いいじゃないですか！
Ooh! Isn't that nice?!
さっきの配信でも言ってくれていたのか、というメッセージが...
We got this message asking if you mentioned that in your stream earlier...
そうなんだ！
Oh, really!
そう、ね、なんか、あのー、こよちゃんね、ずっと団長を『ノエル先輩』って呼んでくれてて...
Yeah, you see, Koyo-chan has always called me "Noel-senpai"...
うんうん。
Uh-huh.
ちょっとそろそろね、そう、先輩呼びじゃなくて、お近づきになりたいなーっていう...
So I thought maybe it's about time to drop the "-senpai" and get a little closer...
おおー！ でも嬉しい！
Ooh~! But I'm so happy to hear that!
いいじゃないですか！
That sounds great!
いろいろ遊んでるし、なんか呼び始めたら呼べそうな気がする！
We hang out a lot, so I feel like once I start calling you that, I'll get used to it!
あはは！
Ahaha!
呼び始めたらね！
Once you start, yeah!
そう、慣れないかもだけど、やっぱ慣れなんだよな、時間かかるかもだけど。
Yeah, it might feel awkward at first, but it just takes getting used to, even if it takes time.
そうね！
That's true!
ぜひ呼び... な、なんだろうな、でも。『ラミたん』『ノエたん』なのか...
I'd love to! W-What could it be, though? "Lamy-tan" and "Noe-tan"?
『ラミたん』『ノエたん』？
"Lamy-tan" and "Noe-tan"?
『ラミたん』『ノエたん』！
"Lamy-tan" and "Noe-tan"!
ノエたん。
Noe-tan.
うん。
Yeah.
ノエたん... ノエ... ノエ...
Noe-tan... Noe... Noe...
ノエたん！ ノエルん？ ノエたん？
Noe-tan! Noel-n? Noe-tan?
ノエるん... ノエたん...
Noel-n... Noe-tan...
ノエ... ノエたんかな？
Noe... Maybe Noe-tan?
あー、ノエ...
Ah, Noe...
うん。
Yeah.
ノエたん？
Noetan?
呼びやすそう。
That sounds easy to say.
ノエたん、ノエたんだよね。
Noetan. It's "Noetan," right?
ノエたんだね。
Yeah, Noetan.
あれ？ノエたんか。
Huh? Noetan, huh?
ノエたんだね。
Noetan, right.
ノエたん。
Noetan.
イントネーション！
That intonation!
ノエたん、ノエ...じゃ、今日はノエたんで行こうかにゃ？
Noetan, Noe... So should we go with "Noetan" today?
下がるほうで？
With the falling tone?
下がるほうで、ちょっとやっていきたいと思います、今日は。
With the falling tone. Let's go with that today!
やったぁ！
Yay!
ありがた〜い。
How nice~
やったぜ！やったぜ！
All right! All right!
さらにちょっと打ち解けられそうになったところで...
Now that we've become a little closer...
うん、はいはい。
Yeah, yes, yes.
これ、これが本当のジャブですね。えー、こちら。
This—this is the real jab. Um, this one.
お、きた！
Oh, here it comes!
「男ひとりで「ちいかわ」の映画を観に行っても大丈夫でしょうか？
"Is it okay for a guy to go watch the Chiikawa movie alone?
周りから白い目で見られたりしないでしょうか？少し不安です。
Will people give me cold looks? I'm a little anxious.
でも、おっさんもセイレーンちゃんや島二郎に会いたいんです」
But this middle-aged guy wants to see Siren-chan and Shima Jiro too."
というの来てますよ。どうですか？
That's what they're asking. What do you think?
あたりめー！
Of course it is!
え、ダメな理由ある？逆に。
Wait, is there any reason you shouldn't? Quite the contrary!
ないない！むしろいいよね！
None at all! If anything, it's great!
だよね！
Right?!
かわいいじゃん！
It's so cute!
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
いや、そうなん、これ、こういうの結構配信でもすでに言ってるんですけど、
Yeah, exactly. I've actually mentioned this on stream before,
それでも悩み多き、あのリスナーさんがいたので...
but there was still a listener who was really worried about it...
何も恥ずかしくないよな。
There's nothing to be embarrassed about.
そうなんだ。ねー、何も恥ずかしくない！
I see. Yeah, nothing to be ashamed of at all!
ないでしょ。
None at all.
うん、てか二人ともちいかわ映画観に行ってるもんにゃ。
Yeah, plus you two both went to see the Chiikawa movie.
うん、行ってる。
Yeah, we did.
いたよね？男ひとりの客さん。
There were solo male customers, right?
もう、いたいたいた！
Oh, totally! There were!
いるいる！ない、しかもグッズもいっぱいつけてる！
Definitely! And wearing lots of merch too!
わかる！わかる！
I know! I know!
そこよ！
That's it!
全然平気だよ。
It's totally fine.
うん、もうね「気にするな」というのを伝えるために紹介しました。
Yeah, I featured it just to tell him, "Don't even worry about it!"
はい！
Yes!
しかもね、あの第5弾発表されたからね！
And besides, you know, Volume 5 was just announced!
あ、そうなんだね！
Oh, is that right?!
ねー、だから...
Yeah, so...
めじるしアクセね。
The marker accessories!
うん。
Yeah.
より行ってほしい。
All the more reason to go!
ね、ゲットしてきてほしいですよね。
Yeah, we want him to go get one, right?
ね、島二郎をゲットしてください、是非！
Yeah, please go get Shima Jiro, definitely!
はい！
Yes!
ぜひぜひ。
By all means!
はい、それでは続いてこちらいきましょう。女の子からです。
All right, let's move on to the next one. It's from a girl!
お！
Oh!
ほう！
Oho!
「3人は学生時代スクールメイクなどしてましたか？？
"Did the three of you do school makeup when you were students??
私もしたいのですがよくわからないので参考にしたいです。
I want to do it too, but I'm not really sure how, so I'd like some advice.
おすすめのコスメなどあれば聞きたい」
If you have recommended cosmetics, I'd love to hear them."
結構ね、おすすめコスメは何個か来てました、女子が。
Quite a few girls actually sent in questions asking for recommended cosmetics.
あー、そうなんだ！
Oh, really!
見てくれてるみたい。嬉しいですね。
Looks like they're watching. That's nice to hear.
へー、ありがたいですね。
Heh~ We really appreciate that.
してた？スクールメイク。
Did you guys do it? School makeup.
スクールメイク...
School makeup...
え？薄メイクみたいな、ナチュラルメイク？
Eh? Like light makeup, natural makeup?
どうなんだろう？多分、学校行く時にメイクなのか...
I wonder? Maybe makeup when going to school, or...
あとは学生時代にメイクってしてた？
or just did you wear makeup during your student days?
してた。
I did.
いやー...
No...
してた。
I did.
お、してた！
Oh, you did!
え、学校行く時もしてた？
Wait, even when going to school?
し、してた。
I-I did.
ええーっ！
Eeeh?!
すごい！
Amazing!
してた...けど...
I did... but...
へえー！
Wow!
え、二人ともしてなかった？
Wait, did neither of you do it?
え、こよは、学校行く時はしてなくて、
Well, Koyo didn't do it when going to school,
あの、お出かけの時に、
but when going out,
ちょっと見よう見まねでしてた。
I tried doing a little by copying what I saw.
あー、なるほどなるほど。
Ah, I see, I see.
ノエル先輩...ノエたんは？
Noel-senpai... what about Noetan?
あ、ノエた...ノエたんはねー、あのー...
Ah, Noeta... Noetan, well, um...
いや、でもどうだろ...その、ま、スクールメイク...
No, but I wonder... Like, school makeup...
学生時代だから、え、高校とかってことだよね？
It says student days, so like, high school, right?
あ、そうそうそう！
Ah, right, right, right!
そうでしょ。
Probably so.
えー...なんかね、興味はあったけど、
Hmm... I was interested,
してなかったかなー。なんか厳しかった。
but I don't think I did. It was kind of strict.
あー、学校が？
Ah, the school was?
学校が厳しくて。
The school was strict.
うんうん。
Yeah, yeah.
なんかしてる子はいたんよ。
There were girls who did it, though.
でもすぐ怒られてて。
But they got scolded right away.
あ、そりゃそうだ。
Ah, well of course.
うん、横目で見て、「あ、厳しいなー、
Yeah, I watched from the corner of my eye and thought, "Ah, they're strict,
じゃ、まだ早いか」って思って。
so it's too early for me yet."
ああー、そんな感じだったんだ。
Aah, so that's how it was.
正しいと思うけどなー。
I think that was the right call, though.
校則はそれぞれあるもんね。
Every school has its own rules, after all.
え、お出かけの時もしてなかった？
Wait, you didn't even do it when going out?
お出かけの時はねー、ちょっと、あの見よう見まねで、プチプラあるじゃんか。
When going out, you know, I tried imitating a bit with drugstore makeup.
わかるー！
I know that feeling!
400円とか500円のね、クリームチークとか買って、
I'd buy like a 400- or 500-yen cream blush,
チークだけ塗ってた黒歴史がある。
and I have this cringe past of only applying blush.
え？！
Eh?!
チークだけ？！
Just blush?!
確かに今思うと...
Looking back now, for sure...
やっぱさ、トータル大事じゃん？
you know, the total balance is what matters, right?
そうだね、全体のね。
Yeah, the overall look.
そういうのを気にせず、口紅だけとかさ、
Without paying attention to that, doing just lipstick,
チークだけっていう、なんか本当に下手くそだった思い出があるから...
or just blush—I have memories of being really terrible at it, so...
ちょっとね、そこは恥ずかしいなって感じだったけど。
it was a bit embarrassing looking back.
チークオンリーはなかなか見んかもね。
Blush-only might be pretty rare, yeah.
そうだねー。
Yeah, true.
ラミィちゃん、なんかばっちりしてそうな感じ？
Lamy-chan, did you do full makeup?
ばっちりね。
Full makeup, yeah.
ラミィはしてたね。なんか結構コスメ好きだったから。
I did! I was really into cosmetics, you see.
おー！
Oh!
おしゃれ！
Stylish!
ま、別に誰に見られるわけでもなく、
Well, not that anyone was paying attention to me,
スクールメイクしてましたね。
but I definitely wore school makeup.
えー、なんかコツというかさ、スクールだったからこそみたいなやり方とかあった？
Eh~ Were there any tips or techniques specific to doing it for school?
学生時代の...
Back when you were a student...
あ、でもやっぱアイラインめっちゃ濃く引いちゃうとさ、バレちゃうじゃん？
Ah, but if you draw your eyeliner super thick, you'll get caught, right?
あ、確かに。
Ah, true.
あ、バレないようにやってたんだ！
Ah, so you did it so you wouldn't get caught!
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
一応ね、一応。
Just in case, you know.
バレないようにというか、薄めに？薄めにやってた？
Rather than avoiding detection, you mean lightly? You applied it lightly?
うんうんうん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
でもなんか結構色々、眉とかも整えてたし。
But I shaped my eyebrows and stuff quite a bit, too.
ああ、確かに。
Ah, true.
眉毛整...
Eyebrow sha...
眉ねー！
Eyebrows, right!
大事！
Crucial!
大事。
Crucial.
大事だよね。
They're really important.
そう、やっぱ眉毛はね、顔の印象だいぶ変わりますからね。
Yeah, eyebrows really change the impression of your face, after all.
うん、だからだいぶナチュラルメイク。CANMAKEとかも使ってたよ。
Yeah, so it was pretty natural makeup. I used CANMAKE and stuff too,
あのプチプラの。
you know, the affordable brand.
やっぱCANMAKEですよ、やっぱ。
CANMAKE is where it's at, really.
王道だよね。
It's the classic choice.
神だね。
It's a lifesaver.
CANMAKE今も使ってて、結構。
I still use CANMAKE quite a bit now, too.
うん、可愛いしパッケージがね。
Yeah, and the packaging is cute.
そう、可愛い、安い、しかも結構質が高い...
Yeah, cute, cheap, and surprisingly high quality...
...と思っている。
...in my opinion.
めっちゃいい。なんかその、この価格だけどチークの塗りとかもすごい綺麗に出るし。
It's so good. At that price, even the blush goes on looking really pretty.
そうそう。なんかね、コスメすごい好きな友達がいるんですけど、
Exactly. You know, I have a friend who's super into cosmetics,
その子もCANMAKE結構取り入れてて。
and she incorporates CANMAKE quite a lot too.
高いお金にこう固執しなくても全然素敵なね、メイクできるなっておすすめしたかったです。
You don't have to fixate on expensive products to do wonderful makeup, so I wanted to recommend it.
あー、そうだね。
Ah, that's true.
おすすめだね。
A great recommendation.
ていうか今やね、結構100均とかでもさ、メイクグッズって売ってるじゃないですか。
Besides, nowadays they sell makeup products even at 100-yen shops, right?
確かに、ある。
True, they do.
あれもなんか、結構普通に使えるんよ。
Those are actually totally usable too.
え、そうなんだ！
Wait, really?!
そうそうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
使ったことなかった。
I've never used them.
おすすめとかある？
Do you have any recommendations?
あ、でもアイライナーとかは全然発色もいいし、落ちにくいし。
Ah, but eyeliners have really good color payoff and don't smudge easily.
あ、そうなんだ、すご！
Ah, really? Amazing!
そう、全然使えるよ。めっちゃいいよ。
Yeah, you can totally use them. They're great.
学生だとやっぱね、高いからね、メイク道具も。
When you're a student, makeup tools are expensive, after all.
そうですよね。
That's so true.
月1ぐらいの感じになるじゃん、1個ずつ。
You can only buy them like once a month, one item at a time.
そうするとやっぱ100均、嬉しいよな。
When that's the case, 100-yen shops are such a lifesaver.
100均ね。
100-yen shops, yeah.
気軽にね。
So accessible.
ぜひ参考にしてみてください！
Please check them out for reference!
はーい！
Yes!
はーい。では次、ちょっと男子からね、いきましょうかね。たぶん男子。
All right. Next, let's take one from a guy. Probably a guy.
「美女3人のフェチが知りたいです！」
"I want to know the fetishes of the three beauties!"
うわー！
Whoa!
フェチ！
Fetishes!
フェチか... 何フェチある？
Fetish, huh... What kind of fetish do you have?
今ちょっと考えてる。
I'm thinking about it right now.
え、でもね、ラミィ結構ね、やっぱちょっと汗の匂いかもしれないな。
Well, but you know, for Lamy, it might be the smell of sweat.
あー！匂い！
Ah! Scent!
そうだ、言ってた！
Right, you mentioned that before!
そう、ちょっとやっぱみんな... 今さ、ちょっと露出が激しいじゃないですか、今。
Yeah. Like right now, people show quite a lot of skin, don't they?
やっぱでもなんか、ちょっと汗かいてそうなところの匂い嗅ぎたいもんね。
Still, I just really want to smell spots that seem like they've gotten sweaty.
ええー！？
What?!
嗅がせたくないけどな！正直！
I honestly wouldn't want to let you smell mine, though!
そうなんだ。
Is that so?
え、嗅がせたくないよ！
Like, I wouldn't want you smelling me!
汗は汗やで！
Sweat is just sweat!
そうだ！
That's right!
これ前にももしかしたら取り扱ったかもしれない。こよは声。
We might have talked about this before too. For Koyo, it's voices.
そうですね、その時も言ってた気がしますね。
Yeah, I feel like you said that back then too.
あ、声なんだ。
Ah, voice.
声。声はやっぱり、声優さんとか好きだったから、子供の頃から。
Voice. As for voice, I've loved voice actors and stuff since I was a kid.
「あ、この人の声はこんな感じなんだな」みたいなの、ちょっとまず気にしてしまうところありますね。
So I kind of tend to notice first, like, "Ah, so that's what their voice sounds like."
さあ、ノエル先輩！
Now then, Noel-senpai!
ノエたん？
Noe-tan?
ノエたんは？
What about Noe-tan?
今怒られた。「ノエたん！」
I just got scolded. "Noe-tan!"
ノエたんです。ノエたんは... 手かも。
It's Noe-tan. For Noe-tan... it might be hands.
手？
Hands?
手のどういう手がいいかと言うと？
When you say hands, what kind of hands do you like?
え、むちむちな手が好き。
I like plump, squishy hands.
赤ちゃんみたいな？
Like a baby's?
そう、赤ちゃんみたいな手が、好き。
Yeah, I like baby-like hands.
へえー！
Whoa!
笑ってよ！
Don't just stare, laugh!
意外！
That's unexpected!
なんか触ったら気持ちよさそうとか、そういう感じ？
Like, does it seem like it'd feel nice to touch, or something like that?
も、そうだし、なんかこう見た目的にも可愛いなと思って。
That too, and I also just think it looks cute visually.
ああー。
Ahh.
で、なんかやっぱさ、手とかって骨格とかなんかな、骨格でさ...
And you know, hands are determined by bone structure or whatever...
見た目的には全然細いのに、なんか手だけさ、ちょっとむちむちしてる女の子とかいるじゃん。
Even when a girl is really slender overall, her hands can still be a little plump, right?
確かに、確かに。
True, totally.
そう、なんかそういう子に憧れるんだよね。団長さ...
Yeah, I really admire girls like that. Because for me...
ま、ちょっと今画面にはね、映ってないけど、手が結構やっぱり...
Well, they aren't on screen right now, but my hands are actually pretty...
骨、骨がちょっと角張ってるんだよね。これがちょっとコンプレックスで。
bony, the bones are kind of angular. I'm a bit self-conscious about it.
えー、そうなんだ。
Huh, really?
そう、なんか丸みがあるおててはずーっと憧れてるの。
Yeah, I've always admired soft, rounded little hands.
へえー！そうなんだー！
Wow! I had no idea!
知らなかったー。
I didn't know that.
言わないよ！
I don't go around telling people!
なんかクリームパンみたいな手とか、もう大好き！
Hands that look like cream buns, I just love them!
握りたくなるかもね。
Makes you want to hold them, huh.
そう！なるほどー！
Yes! That makes sense!
なんか今コメント欄に「吉良吉影」って言われてて...
Though the chat is calling me "Yoshikage Kira" right now...
いやいや、そんな... 切ったりそこまでだ！
No, no, not like cutting them off... that's too far!
そこまでだな。
That's definitely too far.
怖い。
Scary.
なるほど、ちょっと気にしちゃうなというところですかね。
I see, so it's just something that catches your eye, then?
そうですね、もうフェチですね。
Yeah, definitely a fetish.
えー、そうなんだ。なるほど。
Huh, I see. Got it.
では、もう一個ちょっと... ノエル先輩に聞きたい... 我々前回話してるやつなんですけど...
Then, there's one more thing I want to ask Noel-senpai... It's something we discussed last time...
ノエたんに？
To Noe-tan?
ノエたんに！ノエたん、アテレコありがとうございました。
To Noe-tan! Noe-tan, thank you for doing the voiceover!
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
なんか友達止まりになっちゃいそうな感じがする...
I feel like they'd just end up staying in the friend zone...
ああ、まあね。
Ah, well, yeah.
好きな男の子が下ネタめっちゃ言ってたら、でもちょ、やっぱ嫌だな。
If a guy I liked was making a ton of dirty jokes, though, I'd really hate that.
ああー、確かに。
Ah, definitely.
なんか、ちょっと... ちょっと幻滅することもあるかもね。下ネタの質によっては。
Like, you might end up getting a bit disillusioned. Depending on the kind of dirty jokes.
内容によってはね。 / うん、うん。
Depending on the content, yeah.
え、でも、この質問が来るってことは、
But wait, the fact that this question was sent in...
言いながらモテたいってことなのかな？
does that mean he wants to be popular while still saying them?
どうなんだろう？ / 「俺は下ネタを言いたいんだ！」
I wonder? / "I wanna make dirty jokes!"
「言っちゃう！」みたいな。 / 欲望！ / 欲望！
"I just blurt them out!" kind of thing. / Pure desire!
「僕もそれでモテたら嬉しいな」みたいな。
"And I'd love it if I could still be popular like that," kind of thing.
なんか言っちゃうタイプだから、「このまま生きてて、もうモテるなら、
Since he's the type who blurts them out, maybe it's like, "If I can be popular living like this,
このままで生きるが、これでモテないならやめようかな」みたいな。
I will, but if not, maybe I should stop."
なるほどね。
I see.
いや、これちょっとデカいぞ。この子が今後モテるかモテないか、左右するかもしれない。
Wait, this is kind of huge. This might actually determine whether this guy becomes popular or not going forward.
はっきり言っとかないと！下ネタは多分モテないぞ！
We have to tell him straight! Dirty jokes probably won't make you popular!
そうだね。モテる要素がないかもね。
Right. There's really nothing about it that attracts girls.
確かに、確かに。モテたいなら、ちょっと控えたほうが。男子だけの場とかでね、
Definitely, definitely. If you want to be popular, you'd better hold back. Just when it's guys around,
言って発散したらいいんじゃないですかね？
you can let it out and vent, right?
うん。 / はい。 / それができるのは君たち...
Yeah. / Right. / If you can do that, you guys...
じゃなくてさ、ちょっと全然関係ない話していい？ / いいよ。 / お？
Aside from that, can I mention something completely unrelated? / Sure. / Oh?
あのさ、この間さ、友達とね、ご飯に行ったんですよ。
You know, the other day, I went out to eat with a friend.
そしたら、そこの裏にいた、後ろにいた男の子の4人組ぐらいがいたんですけど、
And behind us, there was this group of about four guys,
えっぐい下ネタ言ってて。
and they were talking about really nasty dirty stuff.
うわー！ / 気まず！ / うわー！えー？
Ugh! / Awkward! / Ugh! Really?
もうずーっと、最初から最後まで下ネタ言ってて。
Like constantly, from start to finish, they were talking dirty.
マジか。
Seriously?
ま、でも、なんだろ、こっちまで聞こえちゃうのはあれだけど、 / ま、でもね、飲み屋とかならね。 / そうそうそう。
Well, hearing it all from over here was uncomfortable, but... / Well, if it's at an izakaya or something... / Right, right, right.
男子ってやっぱそういうもんなのかね？その、我々は知らないじゃん。男子だけの集まりを。
Are guys really just like that? Like, we wouldn't know what it's like when it's just guys together.
みんなそう、そうなの？みんなは。
Are all of you guys really like that?
そうね、聞きたい。コメントのみんなにね、ちょっと問い...
Yeah, I want to ask. Let's ask everyone in the chat...
「でもTPOを弁えてくれ」って言ってる人もいるから。
Though some people are saying, "Keep the time and place in mind."
聞かないであげて！声の大きさ大事ね。 / あ、そうね。
Don't listen in! Volume control is important, huh. / Ah, true.
聞こえてきちゃったんだもん、だって！
I couldn't help hearing it, though!
うん、それはね、そっちのボリュームの問題だからね。
Yeah, that's their volume problem.
「人による」「言わないよ」、あ、「学生はそうかも」だそうです。
"Depends on the person," "I don't say that"... Ah, "Students might be like that," apparently.
ああ、でもそう、学生さんっぽかった、ちょっと。 / ああ、なるほどなー。
Ah, but yeah, they did seem like students, a bit. / Ah, I see.
ちょっと若げの至りやね。 / うん、ちょっと思春期なのかもだね。 / そうですね。
Just youthful indiscretion, then. / Yeah, maybe they're in that adolescent phase. / Indeed.
でも、こよ... こより結構聞いちゃうかも。「こういう話するんだ」
But Koyo... Koyori might actually listen closely, like, "So this is what they talk about!"
気になっちゃうよね。
You do get curious, don't you?
そう、こより女子校だったからさ、分かんないの、本当に学生の男の子たち何考えてるのか。
Yeah, since Koyori went to an all-girls school, I really don't know what schoolboys are thinking.
あ、分析しちゃうんだ？ / うん。 / なるほど。
Ah, so you analyze them? / Yeah. / I see.
ちなみにノエたんは、あの、何校、何校というか、共学、女子校、どっちでしたっけ？
By the way, Noe-tan, what kind of school did you go to? Co-ed or all-girls?
えーっとね、高校まで共学で、大学で女子だった。
Umm, co-ed through high school, and all-girls for university.
おー！結構珍しいタイプ。
Oh! That's a pretty rare pattern.
なるほど、じゃあどっちの目線も知ってるみたいな。 / そう、そうそうそう。
I see, so you know both perspectives. / Right, exactly.
そうだね。一応。 / 一応、わかるけども。
That's true. Pretty much. / Pretty much, I can understand, but...
ま、でも男女気になっちゃうね、なんの話って。
Still, whether guy or girl, you end up curious about what they're talking about.
ね、聞いちゃいます。
Yeah, you end up listening.
はい。ではそんな、共学女子校と女子校の3人それぞれがどうなのかという、
All right, so regarding how the three of us from co-ed and all-girls schools feel...
こちら... / お、なんだ？
Here is this... / Oh, what is it?
3人に恋愛の2択についてお聞きしたいです。
"I'd like to ask the three of you about a two-choice question on romance."
好きな人、恋愛対象に、刺激と安心、どちらを求めますか？
"Do you look for excitement or peace of mind in someone you like or a romantic interest?"
思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくる方か、一緒にいて落ち着く自然体でいられる方、どちらを重視されるでしょうか？
"Do you value someone who keeps your heart racing with suggestive behavior, or someone you can feel calm and natural around?"
私は安心タイプで、好きだよとかは伝えられるのですが、
"I'm the peace-of-mind type and can say 'I like you,'
ドラマのようにドキッとさせるような言動は恥ずかしくてなかなかできません。女の子はどちらのほうが嬉しいですか？
but I'm too embarrassed to do heart-fluttering drama-like things. Which one makes girls happier?"
とのことなので、ちょっとこれ、せーので刺激か安心、どっちか答えてみたいと思います。 / いいよ。 / はい！
So, on the count of three, let's answer whether it's excitement or peace of mind. / Sure. / Okay!
せーの！
One, two, three!
安心！
Peace of mind!
おー！揃ったー！ / おー、揃ったねー！ / 安心が... ここは揃えましたね。
Oh! We all matched! / Oh, we matched! / Peace of mind... We agreed on this one.
その心は、ラミたん？ / あ、ラミ？ / うん。
What's your reasoning, Lamy-tan? / Oh, me? / Yeah.
え、刺激って、その、今書いてあるのは「思わせぶりな言動などで毎回ドキドキさせてくる」
Well, excitement here is described as "someone who keeps your heart racing with suggestive behavior,"
って書いてあるけど、そんな思わせぶりな言動されたら、
but if someone acts suggestive like that,
何、もう困るんだけど！「え、それ何？どういう意味？」
it just confuses me! Like, "Wait, what's that? What does that mean?!"
「何、ラミのこと好きじゃないってこと？どういうこと？なんでそういうことするの？」
"What, does that mean you don't like me? What's going on? Why are you doing that?!"
そうだね。 / なっちゃう、なっちゃう。絶対安心のほうがいいよね。
Exactly. / That's how it ends up. Peace of mind is definitely way better.
うん、ノエたんはどうですか？
Yeah. Noe-tan, how about you?
いや、なんかさ、人生ってさ、生きるって大変やん。
Well, life itself is already tough enough, right?
それなのに、刺激なんていらんです。
On top of that, who needs excitement? I don't want it.
安心がほしい。やばい、優しさがほしいでやんすよ。
I want peace of mind. Oh man, I just want kindness, man.
わかるわー、めちゃくちゃ。
I totally get that, so much.
いや、なんかさ、こう、ずっと一緒にいるっていう前提で考えたくて...
Yeah, like, I want to think about it on the premise of being together long-term...
この恋愛というものを...
When it comes to romance...
あ、何？それは24時間一緒にいるってこと？どういうこと？
Ah, what? Does that mean being together 24 hours a day? What do you mean?
ていうか、もう何だろう...
Or rather, how should I put it...
付き合って、本当行けるならゴールのその結婚、
Dating, and if possible, reaching the goal of marriage,
そして生涯最後までみたいなぐらいなところまで...
and staying together until the very end of life...
墓までね、うん。
All the way to the grave, yeah.
そうそう、墓までみたいなことを考えて、
Right, right. Thinking about going to the grave together,
恋愛というものを考えたときに、
when considering romance like that...
安心がもう、大事すぎない？
Isn't a sense of security just way too important?
ずっと癒やされて安心してい、こうなんかホッとする...
Always being comforted, feeling safe, having that sort of relaxing...
家庭でありたいと思うから、
home you want to create, so...
だから、なんか別に刺激いらんなぁってなる。
it makes me feel like, I don't really need excitement.
まあそうだね、長ーく一緒にいること考えたら、
Well, that's true. When thinking about being together for a long time,
刺激って逆にちょっと困るかもな。
excitement might actually be a bit troublesome.
しかもさ、刺激を求めるってさ、刺激ってさ、なんか慣れてくじゃんか。
Besides, seeking excitement—people get used to excitement, don't they?
いろんな絡みだったりそういう...
Like in various interactions and such...
だからこの場合の刺激っつうのは、最終的にどこまでいく...
So the "excitement" in this case, where does it ultimately end up going...
なんかちょっと怖いね。
That sounds a bit scary.
確かに。怖い。
Indeed. Scary.
そう、長く見たときに、なんか、ちょっとした刺激じゃもう...
Right, over the long run, small thrills won't even...
もう全然反応しなくなっちゃいそう。
won't get any reaction at all anymore.
SMに発展していってしまうのか...
Would it develop into S&M...?
大富豪？
Tycoon?
そっちにいく？
You go in that direction?
うん、まあなんか刺激とか最初の3回ぐらいまででいいんじゃないかなみたいな...
Yeah. Well, I feel like excitement is fine for just the first three times or so...
感じよね。
right?
まあなんか付き合う前とかに、そういうドキドキ感があればいいんじゃない？
Having that heart-fluttering feeling before dating or something is enough, right?
勝手にドキドキするだろうしね。
Yeah, your heart flutters on its own anyway.
いや、お前... 勝手にやめて。
Hey, you... Don't do it on your own!
一人でにね。
All by yourself!
はい、ということで、まあ多分わかんないですけど多くの女の子は安心なんじゃないかなという...
All right, so while I don't know for sure, I think most girls prefer security...
そうですね。
Definitely.
はい。次、ちょっと恋愛とはまた別のとこなんですけども...
Yes. Next, moving on to a slightly different topic from romance...
「脱毛しようか迷っています (男性)」
"I'm wondering whether to get hair removal (male)."
しろ！
Do it!
早い！早い！食い気味！
Fast! That was fast! Cutting right in!
「女性から見て毛があるのとないのとでは結構印象変わってくるのでしょうか？」
"From a woman's perspective, does having hair versus not having hair change the impression much?"
え？「しろ」なの？
Eh? You say "do it"?
え、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛とかしたほうがよくない？
Wait, wouldn't it be way better to at least get beard removal?
だって、いやなんかさ、毎朝毎朝さ、剃ってるんでしょ？
I mean, they have to shave every single morning, right?
あ、確かに。
Ah, true!
だし、なんかこういう何？刃がさ、やっぱ肌に当たると刺激になってさ、そこが荒れちゃったりとかするわけじゃないですか。
And having razor blades contact skin causes irritation and makes it break out or get rough, right?
あ、そうなんだ。
Ah, is that so?
えー！？
What, really?!
そういうの考えると、もう絶対ヒゲ脱毛なんてラミィが男性だったらまず真っ先にやる。
Thinking about that, if Lamy were a man, beard removal is the very first thing I'd do.
ま、確かに。
Well, true.
ヒゲ脱毛しろ！
Get beard removal!
生やしたい人は別にそのまま生やしてくださいだけど、剃ってる人はね。
People who want a beard can just grow one, but for people shaving...
楽になると思うけど。
I think it would make life much easier.
うん。ノエル団長はそこまでって感じ？
Yeah. But Captain Noel doesn't feel that strongly about it?
なんか、団長はあんまり... その...
Well, Danchou doesn't really... like...
いや、ラミィはさ、その人のこと思って言ってくれてるじゃんか。
Lamy is saying that out of concern for the person, right?
あ、そういう視点があるんだって思ったけど、団長はちょっとね、
I thought, "Ah, that's a good perspective," but as for Danchou,
自分の好みで言うと、なんか本当にどっちでもよくて。
in terms of my own preference, I really don't mind either way.
え？なんかさ、毛？
Like... body hair?
毛があったときにね、毛ってさ、意味があるところに入るわけじゃん。
When there's hair, it grows where there's a purpose for it, right?
あー、守るためね。
Ah, to protect the body, yeah.
毛深い人はその分身体をなんかも守んなきゃいけないのかなと思って。
So if someone is hairy, I think maybe their body needs that much extra protection.
ほら！
See!
ストーリーなんだね。
You see a whole story in it!
ストーリー、なんかすごいクマさんみたいだなという感じで、
A story, like, "Aww, they're just like a big bear,"
可愛いなって。
and thinking it's cute.
いや、でもなんか本当にね、脱毛しようかしないかで言うならば、
But really, when it comes to deciding whether to get hair removal or not,
脱毛しようか迷ってんだったらした方がいいと思う。
if you're hesitating, I think you should do it.
あー、確かに。
Ah, true.
そう、女子から見て毛があった方がとかない方がとかは、
Yeah, whether women prefer hair or no hair
色々人それぞれだと思うけど、やっぱ自分自身だと思うな。
varies from person to person, but ultimately it's about yourself.
しかも脱毛って痛い！
Plus, hair removal hurts!
そうね。お金もかかりますし。
That's right, and it costs money too.
から、その... 周りからどう見られるかよりも自分自身が
So rather than how others perceive you,
やって、なんかこう過ごしやすいかでやった方が後悔もないと思うので。
doing it based on whether it makes your own life more comfortable will leave no regrets.
確かにそうかも。
That's true, yeah.
まあね、そういう感じで団長は。
Well, that's how Danchou feels about it.
あれだよね、毛がある人を見て「毛があるな、嫌だな」と思うことはないよね？なんか...
Right? Looking at someone with body hair, you never think, "They have hair, gross," right?
そうだね、そんな毛深い人を見たことがない。
Right, I've never really seen anyone that hairy.
道行く人...
Passersby on the street...
でしかないから、そこまで考えることそんなないけど、
They're just people on the street, so you don't think about it that deeply,
ま、その脱毛したからいいとかしてないからいいとか、そういう印象の変化っていうのはないのかなみたいな。
but whether getting it removed is good or not doing it is good—it doesn't really change the impression.
感じ。「あ、剃る人なんだな」
It's just like, "Ah, they shave,"
「あ、毛そのままの人なんだな」それだけって感じがする。
or "Ah, they keep their natural hair"—feels like that's all there is to it.
うん、なんか本当にスタイルだよね。その人の生き様というか...
Yeah, it really is just personal style. Like their way of life...
とか
Or something like that.
ということで あんまり気にしたことないね
So yeah, we haven't really worried about it much.
うん
Yeah.
ま でもなんかヒゲを そう脱毛したいと迷ってるなら した方がいいっていうラミたんの圧...
But if you're torn on getting your beard removed, my pressure is to just go for it...
絶対だって 困ってるそうだもんね きっとその
Definitely! They clearly seem troubled by it, like...
やっぱ毎回剃ったりとかね 肌荒れしたりとか
...having to shave every time, getting skin irritation, and all that.
圧倒的に自分がやっぱ脱毛して良かったと感じているから
And personally, I'm overwhelmingly glad I got hair removal myself,
ああ なるほどね / っていうのもあるかな
Ah, I see. / ...so there's that too.
楽ちんだからなーってね
It's just so much easier.
うん 確かにね
Yeah, definitely.
あー 楽ちんではあるな うん
Ah, it really is so convenient, yeah.
意外とね あの 凄い痛いとことか麻酔とかやれる...
Surprisingly, you know, for really painful areas, you can even get anesthesia...
しね。分かんない 顔はどうなの？ヒゲってどうなんだろう 分かんないけど
and all. Though I don't know, how's beard removal? I'm not sure, but...
分かんないけど
I'm not sure either, but...
ね。どうなんでしょうか。ちょっと調べてみてもいいのではないかとおもいまーす
Right. I wonder. I think it might be worth looking into!
うん。はい。
Yeah. Right.
さあ では続きまして、ちょっと変なのいっていいですか？
All right, moving on, can I pick kind of a weird one?
お、いいよ。
Oh, sure!
はい、夜も更けてまいりましたので...
Yes, since the night is getting late...
お風呂で異性に洗わせてもいい場所の限界を教えてください
"Please tell us the limit of what areas you'd let the opposite sex wash in the bath."
謎のおマシュマロが...
A mysterious Marshmallow question...
何それ！？え！？
What is that?! Huh?!
限界？ / 限界！
The limit? / The limit!
誰、この異性って？
Who is this "opposite sex"?
何者なの？
Who are they talking about?
そうなの！なんか...え、店？彼女？どっち？！
Exactly! Like... wait, a parlor? A girlfriend? Which one?!
この...だ、誰なの？異性って誰、誰なの？
Who... who is this? Who's the opposite sex here?!
分かんないけど...
I don't know, but...
でもこよは、彼女なのだとしたら
But Koyo thinks, if it's a girlfriend,
彼女が洗いたいならどこまででもいいんじゃない？って思った
if she wants to wash you, shouldn't anywhere be fine?
どういうこと？その、こよが彼女だったら、ラミィはどこも洗ってもいいってこと？
What do you mean? If Koyo were your girlfriend, you're fine with Lamy washing anything?
あ、違う違う違う！えっ、何？ラミたんが洗ってくれるの？！
Ah, no, no, no! Wait, what? Lamitan, you'd wash me?!
待って、話が変わってくるんだけど！
Wait, that's completely changing the subject!
そうだったらってこと
I mean if that were the case!
え、なんか、あの...どっちだろう。えっと、こよが彼女で、で、えっと...
Wait, like... which way? Um, Koyo is the girlfriend... and, um...
こよが...え、こよが彼女ってちょっと難しいな
Koyo is... wait, imagining Koyo as the girlfriend is a bit difficult.
彼女が、「え、君の全部洗ってあげたいの」って言ってきて
If your girlfriend says, "I want to wash all of you,"
自分も まんざらではないなら、全部洗わせていいんじゃない？
and you're not against it either, shouldn't you just let her wash everything?
あー。 / このマシュマロの人になりきってんの？今
Ahh. / Are you roleplaying as the person who sent the Marshmallow right now?
あ、そうそうそう！なりきった上で。 / なりきった上で？そういうことか / そうそうそうそう
Ah, yeah, yeah, yeah! Getting into character. / In character? I get it now. / Yeah, yeah!
え、でも、でもこのマシュマロの人は
But wait, I thought this Marshmallow sender
団長たちが、その異性が洗うならどこまで許せるっていうフリだと思って聞いてたから...
was asking how much Danchou and the rest of us would allow someone of the opposite sex to wash...
あ、じゃあ「洗ってほしいな」って言う側？言われる側？ / 「洗ってほしいな」？
Ah, so the side asking, "I want you to wash me"? Or the one being asked? / "I want you to wash me"?
「洗ってほしいな」って言われる側？
The side being told, "I want you to wash me"?
この子が、えっと彼女に対して「洗ってほしいな」って言いたいのかもしれないから
Because maybe this person wants to tell their girlfriend, "I want you to wash me,"
そしたら「どこまで求めていいですか？」っていうことにするじゃん
so they're asking, "How far can I ask for?"
どういうこと？どういうこと？！
What do you mean? What do you mean?!
なんか...ちょっと待って！自分の立ち位置が分からない / 自分が誰？！ / 第三者、第三者
Wait a sec, I don't know whose perspective I'm taking! / Who are you supposed to be?! / A third party, a third party!
この子の、この子の彼女だとして、このおマシュマロ主の彼女だとして...
Assuming you're this person's girlfriend—the Marshmallow sender's girlfriend...
で、このマシュマロの主であるこの彼ピくんが、一緒にお風呂に入ろうってことになりました
And this boyfriend who sent the Marshmallow decides to take a bath together.
で、この彼ピくんは、あの洗ってほしいっぽい、自分の体を
And this boyfriend seems to want his body washed.
あ、そういうこと？はい。
Ah, is that it? Okay.
あ、そうそうそう。洗ってほしいっぽくて。ねえ？ / うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. He wants to be washed, right? / Yeah.
ちょっと「洗いっこしようよ」みたいな時に
When they're like, "Let's wash each other,"
「どこまでだったらラインを超えないのか」
he's wondering, "Up to where would it not cross the line?"
凄いね、もうライン超えてると思うんだけど！ / 超えてるか！
That's crazy, I feel like the line is already crossed! / It's already crossed?!
いやもう、お風呂入ってんならもう...もう、ない！ない、そんな...
If you're already in the bath together, then... there's no line left! Not at that point...
あ、そっか...えー。
Ah, really? Huh...
え、でもなんか普通だったら「背中までよな」って思ったりね
But normally, you'd think "just up to the back, right?"
あー、背中を流す？ / うん。
Ah, washing each other's backs? / Yeah.
背中の洗いっこまでなら...
If it's just washing backs...
で、でもラミィがこよの体洗っていいんだったら、どこまででも洗いますけど
B-But if Lamy is allowed to wash Koyo's body, I'll wash anywhere!
嘘ー？！
No way!
え、何何、「どこまででも」ね？
Wait, what? "Anywhere", huh?
ええ、ノエたんもノエたんも、どこまででも洗うよ！
Yeah, Noetan too, Noetan too! I'll wash you anywhere!
ほんまにー？
Really?
洗うけどー。
I would!
えー、僕が男だったら、どこまで洗ってくれるなら、じゃあ...お願いします！
Eh, if I were a guy and you'd wash anywhere... then, please do!
でもさ、え、ラミィ団長の体洗ってくれるって... / うん、言ったけど...
But hey, Lamy, you said you'd wash Danchou's body... / Yeah, you did say that...
あれちょっとややこしいよ、体洗うルーティンが
Her body-washing routine is a bit complicated, though.
ラミィ、ラミィも多分美容にね、色々やってるから、ちょっと...細いかもしれんけど...
Lamy... Lamy also does a lot of beauty care stuff, so she might be a bit meticulous, but...
あ、いい、覚える、覚える！全部！ / スクラブとか...
Ah, it's fine, I'll memorize it all! / Like scrubs...
全部覚える！まずは泡立てるじゃん？ / うん、うん。
I'll memorize everything! First you lather it up, right? / Yeah, yeah.
で、体は洗うけど、あの、大事...あるじゃんね、その下の、大事なところは別の石鹸で洗ってほしい
And you wash the body, but... you know, the sensitive... that important area down there, I'd want washed with a dedicated soap.
ちゃんとそうしてるから！
Because she actually does that!
そうそう！めちゃくちゃ大切だからね！
Right, right! Because it's super important!
ラミィも別の石鹸で洗ってる！
Lamy also washes with a different soap!
あーねでしょ？
Right?
そういうのをちゃんとやってくれるなら、いいよ。
If they properly do that for me, that's fine.
あ、ラミィね！なるほどね。
Ah, Lamy does! I see.
分かった、分かった。全部覚えるわ。
Got it, got it. I'll remember everything.
1から全部全部覚えるから、洗わせてもらっていい？
I'll memorize every single step from 1, so can I wash you?
あ、それなら、それならいいかな。うん。
Ah, if that's the case, I guess that's fine. Yeah.
オーケー、オーケー。任せろ。
Okay, okay. Leave it to me.
いい女すぎるだろ。
She's way too good of a woman.
またラミちゃん...この番組やるとラミちゃんがいい女であることがどんどんね、世間にバレていくだけの...
Whenever we do this show, the fact that Lamy-chan is such a great woman just keeps getting exposed to the world...
いや、ありがたい！
No, I'm grateful!
時間...え、でも...
...time... Wait, but...
いや、もうこよも言ってね。あの、何がどうとかね、全部覚えるんで。
No, Koyo, you tell me too. Like what and how, I'll remember it all.
こよりなんかあんまり特にないから、ラミたんがやってるやつをやってもらった方が綺麗になりそう。
I don't really have any specific preferences, so having you do what Lamy-tan does would probably get me cleaner.
あー、なるほどなるほど。分かった、任せろ。
Ah, I see, I see. Got it, leave it to me.
お任せで。お任せします。
Leaving it to you. I'll leave it to you!
任せろ、任せろ。
Leave it to me, leave it to me.
でも今ので分かったのは、女の子の...
But what we learned from this is,
体を洗いたいんだったら、女の子結構ね、色々気にしてることあるから、
if you want to wash a girl's body, girls care about a lot of different things,
そこを気遣ってあげるといいんじゃないかって感じですかね？
so being considerate about that is the way to go, right?
そうだね！うん。
That's right! Yeah.
それができたら120点だね。
If they can do that, it's 120 points.
ね、120点ですね。
Yeah, 120 points.
ちょっと面白かったんで言っちゃいました。すみません。
That was so funny, I just had to say it. Sorry!
じゃ、ちょっとね、ノエたんだからこその、恋愛相談...
Well then, precisely because we have Noe-tan here,
モードに入りたいと思います！
let's move into Love Advice mode!
はい！
Yes!
恋愛相談、一発目、ご紹介いたしましょう！
Let's introduce our first love advice question!
「団長がいるからということでご相談させてください。」
"Since Danchou is here, please allow me to ask for advice."
「今、自分にはオッペーの大きい彼女がいます。」
"Right now, I have a girlfriend with big breasts."
おおー！
Ooh!
「そして、何を隠そう自分は、大のオッペー星人であります。」
"And truth be told, I am a massive boob lover."
おお。
Ooh.
「ですが...」
"However..."
Win-Winじゃん。
Isn't that a win-win?
Win-Winなんですけど、「彼女にはカッコイイところだけを見せたく、そのことについては言っておらず、」
It is a win-win, but: "Wanting to show only my cool side to my girlfriend, I haven't told her about this,"
「べ、別に興味ねえし、みたいな態度をとってしまいます。」
"and end up acting like, 'I-It's not like I'm interested or anything'."
あ、なんかさっきのキャンディにちょっと繋がる感じだけど。
Ah, that kinda connects to that candy thing from earlier, but...
「このまま我慢してカッコイイ自分を見せ続けるか、」
"Should I keep holding back and continue showing my cool self,"
「それとも引かれることを前提にありのまま自分をさらけ出すのがいいか、どっちがいいんでしょうか？」
"or should I bare my true self even at the risk of being found creepy? Which is better?"
「オッペープルンプルン」だそうです。
"Breasts boing boing," apparently.
これ、でもノエたん、決まってるでしょ、答え。
For this, Noe-tan, the answer is already decided, isn't it?
決まって...でも...
Decided... but...
まぁ何ヶ月かとかね、そういうのも関係すると思うけど、でもさ...
Well, how many months they've been together probably factors in, but...
やっぱ、さらけ出した方がいい！
They should definitely just bare it all!
だって、いつまでそのさ、カッコいい姿...
Because, how long can you keep up that cool act...
いや、最初だけだよ、本当に。
Yeah, it's only at the very beginning, really.
バレる！てか何ならバレてると思う、もう。
She'll find out! Or rather, I bet she already knows!
おっぱい星人だということが？
That he's a boob lover?
目線でバレるんじゃないかってコメントが...
There are comments saying, "Wouldn't she notice from his gaze...?"
ああー...
Aah...
どうですか？なんか、感じることある？
What do you think? Do you ever notice that?
いや、なんか団長感じないけど...
Well, I don't really notice, but...
感じたそう、街中とか？
Has anyone felt that, like out in town?
え、なんかあるよね、そのさ。結構コメントとかでもさ、
I mean, people often bring it up, right? In comments too, like,
「大胸筋がでかいと目線とか気にならないっすか？」みたいな。
"With such huge pecs, doesn't people staring bother you?"
あ、気になったこと...ない。
Ah, feeling bothered by it... Never.
ない！？
Never?!
えー！ないの！？
Ehh?! Never?!
絶対コンビニの店員さんとか見ちゃいそうだけど。
I feel like convenience store clerks would definitely look though!
いや、ラミィですら毎回会ったら見てるよ！
Heck, even Lamy looks every single time we meet!
会ったらね？それはそう、見ちゃうよね。うん。
When we meet? Well yeah, that's true, you would look.
それ、感じてないんか。
So you haven't noticed that?
あんまり、もしかしたら、その...そういう感じないような子だったな、
Maybe she's the kind of girl who doesn't really notice,
気づいてないかもしれんけど。
so she might not have realized, but...
え、でもさ、ほら、ラミィとかね、こよちゃんもあるからさ。
Wait, but look, Lamy and Koyo-chan have them too.
感じたりする？街中で。
Do you ever feel it out in public?
ちょっと街中...街中はないな。
Hmm, in town... Not in town.
では無いけど、
Not in town,
でも「あ、今なんかちょっと目線下だな」と思うことはあるかな。
but I do sometimes think, "Ah, their gaze just dropped a bit."
面と向かってね、話すタイミングとかがあるから。
Yeah, when you're talking face-to-face.
そうだね。お店の人とかもね。
That's true. With shop staff too.
いやー、え、でもどうだろう？こよ的には、
Man, but I wonder? Personally, for Koyo...
でも、ちょっとオッペー星人までを急に言って...
suddenly admitting to being a massive boob lover...
なんか、それで何かが起きてしまったらちょっと怖いなって。この子の気持ちになると。
If something bad happens because of that, it feels a bit scary, thinking about her feelings.
そうだね。いきなりはね。
That's true. All of a sudden, yeah.
いきなりだと、「え、もしかしてオッペーが大きいから付き合ったのかな？」とか
If it's sudden, she might think, "Wait, did he only date me because my boobs are big?" or something,
思われちゃうかもだから。怖いかも。
so that could be scary.
付き合ってどれぐらいの期間なのかプラス...
How long they've been dating, plus...
あとはもうちょっと徐々にだね。やっぱ徐々に、うん。
And then just gradually. Doing it gradually, yeah...
っていう、なんか褒める感じで...
like by complimenting her...
難しいよな。いや、確かになぁ。難しい。
It's tough. Yeah, true. It's difficult.
なんか一気に難しくなってきた！確かに。
Suddenly it got so difficult! True.
でも、かっこつけるのは、なんか、あれかな、続かないと思うんだよね。
But putting on a cool act, I feel like you can't keep that up forever.
そうだね。うん。
That's right. Yeah.
「別に興味ねえし」は嘘になっちゃってるから。
Saying "I don't really care" is turning into a lie.
もしそういう言えるようなタイミングが来た時には、
If a timing where you can say it comes along,
「君自身が好きなことは大前提に、おっぱいも大好きだよ」みたいな。
something like: "Loving you as a person is the top priority, but I love your boobs too!"
言うことないだろうけど！ないかな？
Not that anyone would ever say that, though! Would they not?
まぁでもなんかあれだよね。「べ、別に好き...」
Well, but, you know. "I-It's not like I like..."
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
大1年の女子ホロリスです！
"...I'm a first-year college girl and a Hololive fan!"
恋愛相談なんですけど、
"I'd like some relationship advice."
この前 他大学の男性と3回目のデートに行ってきました。
"The other day, I went on a third date with a guy from another college."
3回目なので告白とか何かしらしてくれるかなと思ったんですけど、何もありませんでした。
"Since it was our third date, I thought he might confess or something, but nothing happened."
それから私の気持ちも冷めてきてしまって、LINEとかする気に全くなれなくて、このままでいいのか悩んでます。
"Since then, my feelings have cooled off, I don't feel like texting him on LINE at all, and I'm wondering if this is okay."
私はどうすればいいでしょうか？助けてー！という
"'What should I do? Please help me!' she says."
かわいい！
"So cute!"
ああ、かわいい～
"Aw, that's adorable~"
3回目のデート。
"A third date."
3回目、どうなんですかね？
"What do you think about the third date?"
どうなんだろうな。
"I wonder..."
3回目のデート、何もありませんでした。
"'On the third date, nothing happened.'"
え、これって…うん。
"Wait, is this... Yeah."
デートということは、え、これ付き合ってるって…
"If it's a date, does that mean they're... dating?"
付き合ってないでしょ！ない！
"They're not dating! No way!"
ない。ないけど、3回デートして、
"No. But going on three dates..."
3回一緒に出かけたなら、もう告白とかそういう感じになるかなみたいな。
"If you've gone out three times, you'd kind of expect a confession or something like that."
って思ってた、うん。
"That's what she expected, yeah."
なるほど。冷めちゃったなら… もうそれが答えってね。
"I see. If her feelings cooled... That in itself is the answer."
うーん…て思う。男の子が
"Well, that's what I think. But if the guy..."
内気すぎて、本当は女の子のこと好きなんだけど、
"is super shy, and actually likes the girl,"
なんか告白する勇気がなくて…っていう
"but just didn't have the courage to confess..."
パターンもあると、団長そっちのパターンかなって思ってるけど、
"There is that possibility. I was leaning toward that scenario,"
なんかコメントがさ、結構キープとか言う人もいたりして。
"but in the chat, quite a few people are saying he might be keeping her on the hook."
ああ、それはちょっとあれだね…
"Ah, that's a bit..."
むずいね。 むずい。
"That's tricky. Yeah, tricky."
けど、冷めちゃったなら…どうなんだろうな。なんか…
"Still, if her feelings cooled off... I wonder. Well..."
そうだね。
"Yeah..."
3回目なので告白とかしてくれるかなっていう…ちょっと厳しいこと言うんですけど、
"'Since it was our third date, I hoped he would confess...' To be a little blunt,"
っていう期待をしてるのが、ちょっと、なんか…
"having that kind of expectation in the first place, well..."
あの、今後のためにも、そういう価値観じゃない方がいいかもなーって思った感じがある。
"For your own future, I feel it might be better not to hold onto that mindset."
ほう。というと？
"Oh? Meaning what?"
なんかその3回目のデートでは告白するっていう決まりは全くなかったりとか、
"Like, there's no set rule that someone has to confess on the third date,"
結構この世の中、告白せずなぁなぁで付き合ったり、付き合ったことになったみたいな人たちもいたりもするから、
"and in this world, there are plenty of people who end up dating naturally without an explicit confession,"
その、なんだろう、絶対に起こるイベントではないので、
"so it's not an event that's guaranteed to happen."
なんかその期待してなかったら冷めなかったのかなとか、
"So maybe if she hadn't expected it, she wouldn't have lost interest."
そういうのの考えで見方を変えた方がいいのかなーと思った。
"I thought it might help to look at it from that perspective."
確かに。なんか、あれやね、たぶん。
"True. And you know, maybe..."
その相手が何かやってくれるみたい…男の子が
"expecting the other person to take the initiative... like, that the guy"
その、プロポーズしてくれたりとかさ、「付き合って」って言ったりとか、
"would ask her to be his girlfriend or confess to her,"
受け身になってはいるよね、この相談者さんね。 まあそうだね。
"she's being quite passive here, this listener. Well, that's true."
女の子はね、その願望は確かに… いや、分かるよ！ あるよね。 分かる。
"Girls definitely have that wish... No, I get it! We do! I understand."
だけど、でもね、やっぱり人によっては、
"But still, depending on the person,"
なかなか積極的な男の子じゃない子もいるだろうし、
"some guys aren't very forward,"
付き合うってなると、そこら辺…
"and when it comes to dating, that kind of thing..."
うん、そうだね。でも好きだったら、やっぱ自分からね、動くのも…
"Yeah, true. But if you like him, taking action yourself..."
大事だと思うから。 うん。
"is important too, I think. Yeah."
そう、「どうすればいいでしょうか、助けてー！」ということなので、
"So, she's asking, 'What should I do? Help!'"
本当に、もうこれっきりこの男の子とはいいかなってなったら連絡取らなくてもいいし、
"If you really feel you're done with this guy, you don't even have to contact him anymore,"
でもまだ、ほんのちょっと好きな気持ちがあるんだったら、
"but if you still have even a tiny bit of feelings for him,"
やっぱ言ってみるのいいと思うんだよね。
"I think it's worth speaking up."
なんかここで冷めちゃうのは、ちょっともったいないなって思うな。
"I just feel it's a bit of a waste to lose interest right here."
そう、だって3回目までデートに行ったんだもんね、事実。
"Right, after all, the fact is you went on three dates with him."
うん、時間を割いてね。 ね！
"Yeah, taking time out of your schedules. Exactly!"
お互いね、お互いの時間使って会ってたわけなんだから、たぶん
"You both spent your time to meet up, so probably"
向こうにも好意があることはあるんだろうね。だって3回目もデート行ったんだもんね。
"he definitely has feelings for you too. I mean, he did go on that third date."
うん。でもやっぱちょっと期待しちゃったんだね。
"Yeah. But she built up her expectations a bit too much."
多分ね、そうだね。 うん、多分。
"Probably, yeah. Yeah, probably."
だから、本当に気になってるならね、自分からどんどん行っちゃってもいいんじゃないかな？
"So if you're truly interested, wouldn't it be fine to take the initiative yourself?"
そうですね。なんか一旦、
"That's right. Just, for a moment,"
この期待してた自分を無くして、
"let go of the self that had those expectations,"
で、その告白してくれなかったっていうのも全部無くして、
"and completely put aside the fact that he didn't confess,"
その子が好きかどうか、っていうことを考えてみて、
"and think about whether you actually like him or not."
で、好きなら、4回目行ってみようぜ！
"And if you like him, go for date number four!"
誘ってみてもいいんじゃない？ うん。
"Why not invite him out? Yeah."
でもね、本当に気持ちが冷めちゃったんだったらもう、逆にね、そんな無理していくことはないし。
"Though if your feelings have genuinely cooled off, you really don't have to force yourself to go."
うん、ね、そんな気がします。あとは、これは大人…
"Yeah, I feel the same way. Also, this is an adult..."
...になってっていう感じなんですけど、
...is kind of how it feels, but...
人に期待していいことは1つもないので、
there is nothing good about having expectations of people,
これは恋愛...そう、恋愛でも、恋愛じゃなくても。
so whether it's romance... yeah, romance or otherwise.
そうねー。/ うん。
That's true. / Yeah.
うーん、なんか、やっぱ...なんだろう、期待ってエゴなんで...
Yeah, I feel like... how should I put it, expectations are pure ego...
って思うと、ちょっと楽になるのかな、生き方が、と。
So looking at it that way might make life a little easier, I think.
お前がな、っていうね。/ うん。/ うん。
"Look who's talking," though. / Yeah. / Yeah.
はい。それでは続いて...
Right. Moving on to the next one...
えー、男の子ですね。
Um, this is from a guy.
えっ、と...「グイグイ話しかけに来るのは、
Um... "What kind of intention or background
どんな意図や背景を持っているのか」という、えー、悩み相談でございます。
does someone have when aggressively initiating conversation?" is the question.
おー。/ うん。
Ooh. / Yeah.
えっ、と、「同じ案件作業をしているが、直接会話が少ない後輩女性。
Um, "A junior female colleague whom I work on the same project with, but rarely talk directly to.
職場飲み会開催場所移動前に、後輩女性から
Before heading to the workplace drinking party venue, she threw a jab like,
『今日の飲み会出席ですよね？よく食べるとお聞きしたので、飲ませても大丈夫ですよね？』みたいなジャブな会話が来る。
'You're coming to the drinking party today, right? I heard you eat a lot, so it's fine to make you drink, right?'
偶然にも座席の升席が同じ場所。
Coincidentally, we ended up in the same booth seating.
自分のコミュニケーションは高めと自負しているが、突如迫られると押し込まれるタイプ。
I pride myself on having good communication skills, but I tend to get overwhelmed when approached suddenly.
何かあるのではと背景を見つつ、さりげない会話で終了。
Wondering if there was something behind it, I probed the situation and ended it with casual banter.
その後特に進展なし。今のご時世、何があるか分からないという建前を置く
No progress since then. I'm a chicken who hides behind the excuse of
チキン野郎です。年齢は30代前半です」という。
'you never know what might happen in this day and age.' I'm in my early 30s."
あーー。
Ahhh.
ま、こういう行動を取る女の子、ま、もし自分がこの後輩女子だとしたら...
Well, for a girl who takes this kind of action... if I were this junior female colleague...
「どうなのかな？」みたいな妄想ですね。
...what would it mean? That's what we're imagining.
うん。/ うーーん。
Yeah. / Mmm...
妄想...あ、これはなんか、あれか。相手が好意を持ってるとかそういうのじゃなくて、
Imagining... Ah, wait, is this not about whether she has feelings for him,
なんでこういう...
but why she'd...
「どんな意図や背景を持っているんでしょうか」と。
"What kind of intention or background does she have?"
要するにおそらく、あの...
Basically, in short, um...
この行動してくるって自分のこと好きなの？っていうのを、
"Does her doing this mean she likes me?"
その女子ってどうなの？って聞きたいんだと思う。
is what he wants to ask girls about.
ああー。/ なるほどー。
Ahh. / I see.
でも、あれだよね、実際に...
But, you know, actually...
なんだろう、向こうからのアクションとしては...
what should I call it, as far as actions from her side go...
あの、「今日飲み会来ますよね？いっぱい飲めますよね？」って言われたこと...
being told, "You're coming to the drinking party today, right? You can drink a lot, right?"...
うん。/ だ、だけだよね？
Yeah. / ...is that all there was?
確かに今書いてある内容だとそれだけかも。
True, based on what's written here, that might be all.
うん。
Yeah.
そう、同じ升席とかはあったけど。
Right, though they were at the same booth.
うん、うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
そんなに...何、何にもなくても聞く...かな？みたいな内容って感じ？
Is it the kind of thing you'd ask even if there was nothing to it, you think?
まあ、うーーん。
Well, hmm...
なんか、こう...ま、そう、飲み会に行くっていうさ、きっかけっていうか、あるから、
Like, well, going to a drinking party gives you an occasion,
とりあえず...ま、飲み会前でちょっとテンション...
so for now... getting a bit hyped before the party...
ま、飲み会ってテンション上がるものか分かんないけど、
Though I don't know if drinking parties get people hyped,
飲み会でテンション上がって、
but getting hyped for the drinking party,
で、なんか、ま、話しかけた...ぐらいな感じなのかな〜？
and then just... coming over to talk, maybe that's all it was?
うん、うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
っていう感じだよね、なんか、本当に。
That's kind of what it feels like, honestly.
まあ、そうだね。でも内容としては、
Well, yeah. But looking at the details,
「グイグイと話しかけに来る」っていうことも別であったのかどうなのか...
was there another time she came aggressively talking to him, or not...
確かにね、回数の問題あるかもねー。
That's true, it might be a matter of frequency.
うん。/ うーーん。
Yeah. / Hmm...
うーん、なんかコメ欄は「何もないぞ、安心しろ」で一致しているみたいなんですけども...
The comments seem to unanimously agree with "There's nothing there, relax," though...
あははは！
Ahahaha!
え、でも、なんか、もし、すごい...
Wait, but what if, like...
え、そんなに俺にだけ話しかけに来るみたいな、
like, "Wait, is she really only coming to talk to me?"
なんかみんなにさ、同じように... / あ、周りにも言ってね。
Or does she do the same with everyone... / Ah, saying it to everyone around too.
そうそうそう。なんか飲み会の人数が増やしたくてみんなに言ってる可能性もあるかなー。
Right right right. There's also a chance she's saying it to everyone to get more people to come.
あーー。
Ahh.
その、でも自分ばっかりいろんなこと聞いてくるなってもし思うのであれば、
But if he really feels like she's only asking him all kinds of things,
なんか聞いてもいいのかなって思っちゃった。
I felt like maybe he could just ask her.
何を？
Ask what?
「そんなに、なんか俺のこと気にしてくれてんの？」みたいな。
Like, "Are you paying that much attention to me?"
ちょっと軽く。そんなグイグイ来てるなら、こっちも軽く...
Just lightly. If she's pushing that hard, then lightly on this end...
ジャブ打つ？ / ジャブ打つ。
Throw a jab? / Throw a jab.
ジャブ...いや、昨今...
A jab... No, these days...
昨今！言葉が出たよ！
"These days!" The word came up!
この前私言ってたけど！
I said that just the other day!
そう、なに...ムズいんだよね、その...
Yeah, like... it's so tricky, that...
この方も心配してますしね、ちょっと。
This person is worried about it too, a bit.
そうなんだよね、すごい慎重派な方なんで。
Exactly, he's a very cautious person.
だから、もう、本当に...うーん、なんだろう？
So really, like... hmm, what could it be?
やっぱグイグイ系だったら...
If she's the aggressive type...
え、なんか、やっぱ昨今ね、結構...
Well, these days, apparently quite a lot of...
...あるらしく...
...happens, so...
やばい、こより駄目そうだ、コンプラ違反で。
Uh oh, Koyori's gonna fail compliance at this rate.
こよちゃん男の子でこういう悩める小羊だったら、ちょっとやばかったかもね。
If Koyo-chan were a boy and a troubled sheep like this, it might've been dangerous.
やばかったかも！女で良かったな、ギリギリ！あははは！
It might've been! Glad I'm a girl, by a hair! Ahahaha!
何なんだ！
What is that even!
まあ...そう、なんかグイグイ...その、まだね、情報も薄いしってことは、
Well... yeah, about being aggressive... there's not much info yet,
そんなに他でグイグイエピソードが揃ってないってことだから、
which means there aren't many other aggressive anecdotes,
一旦普通に、なんか...なんだろう、仕事続けて、
so for now, just... you know, keep working normally,
普通な会話やってでいい気がするな。
and stick to normal conversation, I feel.
そうですね。
That makes sense.
うん、そうだね。
Yeah, that's true.
多分そんな、あの、意識...
She probably isn't consciously...
...して、多分、結構いろんな人に話しかけるタイプの女性だったんじゃなかろうか、という...
...and so, she was probably just the type of woman who talks to a lot of people...
性格な感じかも。 / だな。 / うん。
It might just be her personality. / Yeah. / Right.
あれだね、「2人でご飯行きましょう」とか言われたらもう一回考えて、みたいな...
Like, if she says "Let's go eat just the two of us," then maybe reconsider...
あ、そうだねー。 / 感じかもねー。 / うん、うん。
Ah, that's true. / That might be the way to go. / Yeah.
はい！ということでーす！
Yes! So that's that!
はい！じゃあ、ちょっとあと2つ読んでもいいですかー？ / あ、もちろん！
Okay! Then, would it be alright if I read two more? / Ah, of course!
どうぞどうぞ！ / 女の子と男の子それぞれ行こうと思うんですけれども、
Go right ahead! / I was thinking of doing one from a girl and one from a boy...
かわいいやつです！え、学生の女子大生なんです！
This one's so cute! She's a student—a female college student!
お、女子大生！ / お！大生！女子大生！
Ooh, a college girl! / Oh! A college girl!
「今絶賛片想い中なのですかが、」 / あら、かわいい！
"I'm currently in the middle of a big crush, but..." / Aw, how cute!
「どうすれば相手に振り向いてもらえますか？」
"How can I get him to notice me?"
「モテる行動とか、ヘアスタイルを教えてほしいです！」
"Please tell me what behaviors or hairstyles attract guys!"
「ちなみに、ユニバのアトラクション、2人で乗ったことあります！」
"By the way, we've ridden a USJ ride together, just the two of us!"
幸せかーー！ / かわいいーー！
Aren't you happy enough already?! / So cute!
はい、優勝！ / 優勝！
All right, you win! / A clear winner!
かわいいーー！
So cute!
くっそかわいいーです！ / かわいいねー。
She's ridiculously cute! / So adorable, isn't she?
どうですかー？モテる行動とかヘアスタイル教えてほしいって。
What do you think? She wants to know attractive behaviors and hairstyles.
え、でもさー、その好きな男の子がさ、どんなスタイルが好きなのかにもよらなくない？
But wait, wouldn't that also depend on what kind of style the guy she likes actually prefers?
いや、そうなんだよねー！ / そう、確かにね。
That's so true! / Yeah, exactly.
これはねー。
That's the thing...
あと、この子に似合うとかも大事だったりするしなー...うーん。
Plus, whether it suits her is also pretty important... Hmm...
まあでも、本当に一つだけ言えるのは、もうすでに可愛い。もう、恋してる乙女...
But really, the one thing I can say is that she's already cute. A maiden in love...
うん、かわいいよ！ / かわいい！ / かわいい...
Yeah, she's so cute! / Cute! / Adorable...
もう、いっぱい笑ってね。そう、笑う女の子が、もう最高やから！
Just smile and laugh a lot. A girl who smiles is honestly the absolute best!
あ、確かに！ / そうだね、愛嬌だよ、愛嬌！ / 愛嬌、ほんと。
Ah, definitely! / That's right, charm is everything! / Truly, charm.
「男は度胸、女は愛嬌」ということですね！
"Courage for men, charm for women," as they say!
それまた... / 昔から言うもんね！ / ね、昔から言う...
Bringing out the classics... / It's an age-old saying! / Right, an old saying...
いや、でも大事だと思うよー。うん、笑顔をよく...「俺の前だとすごい人一倍この子笑ってくれるな」とかさ、
No, but I really think it's important. Like, if he thinks, "She laughs so much more around me than anyone else,"
確かに！絶対キュンとくるポイントでしょ。 / うん、うん、うん。
Definitely! That's guaranteed to make his heart skip a beat. / Yeah, totally.
そうだねー、ほんとー。
Absolutely, for real.
なんかこのさ...「幸せー」って思ってるやつを、
So that feeling of "I'm so happy,"
もうなんか伝わるぐらいニコニコしまくり、話しかけたりとかしてもいいのかなって。
I think it'd be great to just beam with smiles so he can feel it, and talk to him like that.
そうだねー。ねー。 / 思っちゃいます。
That's right. / I totally agree.
はい。大事、大事。 / いや、本当に、そうだなー。
Yes. Crucial, crucial. / No, honestly, that's so true.
もう自信持って、すでに可愛いので。あとはあれかもね、なんかさ、
Have confidence, you're already cute! And besides that, maybe...
あの、もしヘアスタイルとか変えたいなら...
Um, if you really want to change your hairstyle...
「なんかさ、好きな女の子の髪型とかあるの？」って聞いて、
You could ask him, "What kind of hairstyles do you like on girls?"
次の日それをやってくる涼宮ハルヒですよ！
And then show up the next day wearing that style like Suzumiya Haruhi!
あー！めっちゃ意識してるじゃーーん！ / 「俺のこと...？！」 / そうそうそう！
Aah! "She's totally conscious of me!" / "Is that for me?!" / Exactly, exactly!
え、そういうのどう、どう思う？
How would that be, what do you think?
え、可愛くない？いいよね！ / いい！かわいい！ / かわいいよねー。
Wait, isn't that adorable?! That's great! / It is! So cute! / Adorable, right?
そういうのやってみちゃってもね、いいかもしれない...なんて思います！
Trying something like that might actually be really great... is what I think!
それやってなんか変な感じになったらどうしようってちょっと今ソワソワしてるんですけど...責任追えないなー(笑)
Though I'm getting a bit fidgety wondering what if it turns out awkward... I can't take responsibility!
まあまあまあね、相手の男の子がどういう感じなのかわかんないからね。 / うん、うん。
Well, we don't know what kind of guy he is, after all. / Yeah, true.
ねー、聞ける関係ならねー。 / でも可愛いでしょう！ / うん、可愛いよねー！ / 素晴らしいですね、はい！
Right, if their relationship is close enough to ask. / But it'd be so cute! / Yeah, so cute! / It's wonderful, yes!
それじゃあ、ラストは男子からの一通行こうかなと思いますけれども...
Now then, I think I'll go with a letter from a guy for the last one, but...
えーと、どっちにしようか...
Um, which one should I pick...
ねー、本当に。もうホクホクしてる！ / うん、ホクホク。本当ねー、恋愛...
Right, truly. My heart feels all warm and fuzzy! / Yeah, warm and fuzzy. Honestly, romance...
楽しいよね、人の恋愛をこう感じるだけでも！ / そうだねー！ / うん！
It's so fun just experiencing someone else's love story like this! / It really is! / Yeah!
じゃあ、こちらはやっぱりちょっとノエル先輩ということで、ちょうど...
Then, for this one, since Noel-senpai is here...
あ、ノエたんということでね、ちょっとそういうやつですね。 / ほー。 / あ、ノエたんね！はい！
Ah, since Noe-tan is here, it fits this kind of question. / Oh~ / Ah, Noe-tan! Yes!
「大人の女性ならではの魅力をお持ちの、すのすの&ノエたんさんに質問です！」 / あらー！ / お、あらあら！
"A question for Sunosuno and Noe-tan, who possess the charm of mature adult women!" / Oh my! / Oh, ara ara!
「私はいつか、素敵なお姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いをして、お互いに支え合えるような関係を築きたいと思っています。」
"Someday, I hope to date a lovely older-sister type of woman and build a relationship where we support each other."
「そこで質問なのですが、お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣や、」
"So my question is, what is the secret to dating an older-sister type of woman,"
「こういう男性だといいなと思うポイントなどはありますでしょうか？」
"and what qualities in a man make you think, 'This kind of guy is great'?"
「ぜひお二人の意見、あ、3人ですね、の意見やアドバイスを聞かせていただけると嬉しいです！」という...
"'I'd love to hear your two—ah, three—opinions and advice!' ...is what he says."
あらあら、あらあら！ / 大人の女性、あらあら！
Ara ara, ara ara! / Mature women, ara ara!
あらあら、大人のお姉さんに憧れている！ / ホロライブのあらあら。
Ara ara, yearning for a mature older sister! / Hololive's ara ara.
お姉さんタイプの女性とお付き合いするための秘訣...
The secret to dating an older-sister type of woman...
これどうなんですかね？ / お姉さんもね、色んなタイプがいるからねー。 / そうねー。
What do you think about this? / There are all kinds of older sisters, after all. / That's true.
じゃあノエたんタイプのお姉さん。優しい、ほんわかしたお姉さんと付き合うには...
Then how about a Noe-tan type? To date a gentle, warm-hearted older sister...
うん
Yeah.
あり...
It's...
えー？
Huh?
え、でも、そうだな...
Well, let's see...
なんか普通に...
I feel like normally...
変にさ、背伸びしなくていいと思っていて...
you don't need to try awkwardly hard to act mature...
そうね。
Right.
一貫してるね。
You've always been consistent about that.
そうだな。
That's true.
そう、なんか本当にこう真面目に生きて、
Yeah, just living earnestly,
なんか精一杯、精一杯で頑張ってるところとかを...
and doing your absolute best at everything...
なんか結構、あれなんじゃないかな...
I think that's really what does it...
そう、せ...なんて...感じが、ちょっと難しいな。
Yeah... it's kind of hard to put into words.
自分がさ、お姉さんタイプでいいのかと思いながら...
While wondering if I even count as the "older sister" type...
お姉さんだよ！
You definitely are!
お姉さん！お姉さん！
An older sister! For sure!
甘やかしてくれそうっていうのが、なんかお姉さん感...
The feeling that you'd pamper someone gives big older sister vibes...
そうだね。
Yeah.
なんか本当に、え、まじめ...なんだろう、
Just really... what is it...
精一杯、精一杯頑張ってる姿とかが...
seeing someone giving it their absolute all...
ま、それはさ、なんかお姉さんとか関係なく、人としてなんか素晴らしいと思うからさ。
Well, regardless of being an older sister, that's just admirable as a person.
なんかそ...そんな感じかな。なんか...
So I guess that's how it is.
特にこういう、ね、あのこういう所がいいみたいなさ、ピンポイントでちょっと言えなくて申し訳ないけど...
Sorry I can't pinpoint an exact trait like, "I like this specific thing," but...
一生懸命ね。
Doing your best, right.
一生懸命なんか生きてる人は、すごい魅力的だなって思う。
I think someone living their life with all their might is so attractive.
で、そういう人を甘やかしたいなって、すごい思う。
And it really makes me want to pamper someone like that.
うわー！「今日お仕事頑張ったー！」
Whoa! "I worked hard today!"
「ママ～！ママ～！」
"Mommy~! Mommy~!"
「褒めて褒めて～！」
"Praise me, praise me~!"
ってことですかね？
Is that what you mean?
ってやっていいってことですよね？
So it's okay to do that, right?
うーーん...
Well...
え、でもちょっと重いんですけど、そのお姉さんに好かれるって、なんかそのバブ味とかさ、
But to be serious for a second, when it comes to being liked by older women, like having that baby vibe...
あの、甘えるタイプがやっぱりお姉さんに好かれるのかな、みたいな、こう...
you have this image that it's the clingy, pampered type that older women like,
あの、二次元脳というか、イメージがあるじゃないですか。
like from anime or manga, right?
だからといって、その「バブバブ～」で行きる...
But even so, going through life acting like a baby...
ではないよなって思うんですけど、どうでしょうか？
surely isn't the right way to go, right? What do you think?
いや...でもバブバブは...
Well... as for acting like a baby...
バブバブ駄目ですか？
Is baby talk no good?
いや、なんかそれもそれで可愛くてあり...
No, in its own way, that's kind of cute and works...
あ、そう？ちょっと包容力がある...！
Oh, really? That's quite broad-minded of you...!
いや、あり！ありだな。だから本当に難しい！
No, it works! It totally does. That's why this is so hard!
そう、なんかこういうことを言って戦略だと思ってて...
Yeah, like approaching it strategically like this...
この、そのマロ主さんがどういうタイプ、こういうのってさ、あの...
But depending on what type the question sender is... with this sort of thing,
なんか良し悪しとかじゃなくて、
it's not about good or bad,
そのタイプってあるじゃん。自分は...
people just have their own types. Like,
そう、例えば背が高いからそういうなんかカッコイイ系で、なんかスタイリングとかしてます、とか。
for example, "I'm tall, so I style myself in a cool, mature way,"
逆に「いや、自分結構幼い、童顔って言われるから、幼い感じで」とか。
or on the other hand, "People say I have a baby face, so I lean into a youthful look."
なんかそういう...なんか戦略？
Having that kind of... strategy?
やっぱ自分にあった感じとかも、
Doing what suits you best,
大事かなと。あと性格とかも。だから...
is important, I think. Your personality too. So...
なんだろうな...うーん。なんかどのタイプでも普通にお姉さんに好かれそうな気がする。
How should I put it... Yeah, I feel like any type can naturally be liked by an older woman.
精一杯に背伸びしてるタイプも、バブバブなタイプも。
Whether it's the type trying their best to act mature, or the babyish type.
逆に、なんか本当にNGなようなことをしなければ...
On the flip side, as long as you don't do anything that's an outright dealbreaker...
なんかいいな...清潔感！清潔感や！
I think it's fine... Cleanliness! It's all about looking clean!
清潔感！出た！
Cleanliness! There it is!
もうこれはあれだね、お姉さんとかお姉さんじゃないとか、もう別で、
At this point, whether they're an older sister type or not doesn't even matter.
人に好かれるということ、みたいな感じですかね。
It's just about being liked by people in general!
難しい！本当なんかちょっと...いや、ムズいね。
It's hard! Really... man, this is tough.
こちら難しいんだけど...
This question is tough...
ま、人にもよるから、みたいなところはあるよね。ラミたん、お姉さんとして...としたら、どう？
Well, it does depend on the person. Lamy-tan, what do you think as an older sister type?
え、ラミお姉さん属性ある？
Wait, do I have the older sister trait?
うん、あんまないか。
Yeah, maybe not.
あるあるある！あるよあるよ！
You do, you do! Totally!
で、でも、みんな「お姉さんっぽい」って言ってるから、この人は。
But everyone says you feel like an older sister, including this person.
おー、そうなんだ。
Oh, really?
ラミにお姉さん属性...
Me, an older sister trait...
いやー、でも...やっぱお姉さんあんま関係ないかもな。人としてになっちゃうな。
Well... but honestly, being an older sister might not even matter. It comes down to who you are as a person.
やっぱそうだな。うん。
Yeah, that's true.
ラミは、なんか尊敬できる人が魅力的に見えるから...
For me, I find people I can respect to be attractive, so...
あー、なるほど。
Ah, I see.
お仕事を頑張ってるとか、
like working hard at their job,
なんか好きなことをね、追っかけてるとか、なんかそういうところに魅力を感じる...かな？
or pursuing what they love... I think that's where I find them charming.
なるほどな。
That makes sense.
やっぱあれかね、その...誠実に生きる...？
I guess it comes down to... living sincerely?
お姉さんとか一回置いといて。
Putting the "older sister" thing aside for a moment.
え、こよは？こよはどうなの？
Well, what about you, Koyo? What do you think?
確かに「お姉さんなのか？」っていう感じではあるんだけど、
It's true that you wonder, "Does being an older sister even matter?"
でもやっぱり支え合えるような関係を築きたいって言ってるから、
But since they mentioned wanting to build a relationship where they support each other,
それを大事にしていくことなのかなー、と思いますね。
I think cherishing that is what matters most.
で、その...でもなんか、お姉さんタイプの女性にとって...
And, well... for an older sister type woman...
Error processing subtitles for this segment.
なるほどね。
I see.
こよりじゃないからな。
You're not Koyori, after all.
いやなんか、こよりがさ...
Well, it's just that...
ちょっとこよりが言えない、答えられない質問だからさ、これさ。
this is a question Koyori can't really answer.
だからその、ありがたいなと思って、答えてもらえて。
So I'm grateful to have you guys answer it.
なるほどね。
I see.
ラミちゃんが女の子として、なんか好きだと感じるのは、なんか他に何かあったりする？
Lamy-chan, is there anything else that makes you feel attracted to someone as a girl?
え、でもやっぱ趣味は大きいんじゃない？
Well, hobbies are pretty important, aren't they?
うん、うん、うん、うん。やっぱそうだよね。
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That's true.
でもさ、この方さ、自分のやりたいことに挑戦してるって書いてあるからさ。
But this person says they're challenging themselves with what they want to do.
ま、お仕事だけでなくって、自分のやりたいこともできてるってことでしょ？
So they're able to pursue what they want beyond just work, right?
うん、多分、多分。うん、うん。
Yeah, probably, probably. Yeah.
すごくいいと思うけどね。めちゃくちゃ素敵だと思いますよ。
I think that's really great. I think it's wonderful.
うん、そうだね。素晴らしい。
Yeah, totally. It's wonderful.
じゃあさ、あのさ、この人多分まだ好きな人とかいるわけじゃないと思うんだけど、
Then, you know, I don't think this person has someone they like yet,
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
その趣味を満喫して、そんな雰囲気を出すのに、なんかちょっとストラップとかつけてみるとか。
but to show that they enjoy their hobbies, maybe having a strap or keychain...
ああー。
Ahh.
例えばさ、我々のようなちいかわ好きとかだったら、ちいかわの...
For instance, if someone likes Chiikawa like us,
あのキーホルダーつけてたりすると、
and they have a Chiikawa keychain on,
「あ、ちいかわ好きで推し活してたりしてるのかな」みたいな。
people might think, "Oh, maybe they like Chiikawa and support it?"
ところから、なんか会話が生まれたりとかね。
And that could spark a conversation.
うん、うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
あるかも。なんかそういうのどうですかね？何にもつけてないとかだったら。
That could happen. What do you think about that, if they don't have anything on right now?
なんか、まあその仕事とかね、普段のそういうTPOにもよるけど。
Well, it depends on their work and the time and place,
確かに、確かに。うん、うん。
Definitely, definitely. Yeah, yeah.
え、でもなんか団長めっちゃいいなーって思ってた。
But didn't Danchou think that was super great?
おー！うーん。
Oh! Mmh.
なんかそれ、それも好きではあるかなーって思って。
I thought you'd like that sort of thing too.
良いと思う。
I think it's good.
うん、うん。
Yeah, yeah.
さっきのマシュマロの人もいたけどさ、ちいかわ一人で男性が見たいけど、みたいに言ってたけど、
Someone sent a Marshmallow earlier saying that as a guy, he wanted to go see Chiikawa alone,
いや、普通にそれって可愛いポイントだと団長思うから、
but Danchou would normally think that's a cute point, right?
そういうマスコットとか、まあ...
So having that kind of mascot or...
モノにもよるのかもしれない。仕事場につけてくから。
Well, it might depend on the item, since you'd bring it to work.
でもなんかいいなーって思う。
But I think it's really nice.
思います。
I think so too.
そうだね。
Right.
思います。はい。
I think so too. Yes.
話しかけるきっかけになりそうですね。
It seems like a great conversation starter.
うん。そういう隙を作りつつ、
Yeah. Creating an opening like that,
でも「お仕事頑張る君は素敵だよ」ということでね。
but also knowing "You're wonderful for working hard!"
うん。はい。はい、偉い！
Yeah. Yes. Good job!
で、締めたいと思いまーす！
And with that, I'd like to wrap things up!
すいません、ちょっと拾いたいのが色々あって、
Sorry, there were so many topics I wanted to get to,
時間ちょっと長くなっちゃったんですけれど、
so we ran a little long, but...
はい！今日はどうでしたか、ノエたん？
Yes! How was it today, Noe-tan?
いや、もう出れてよかった！楽しかったー！
Man, I'm so glad I came on! It was so fun!
なかなかやっぱね、このガチトークだから、
Because this is "Gachi Talk,"
本当にガチな話いろいろ聞けたりできたりして、
we got to hear and have really serious, genuine talks.
あとマシュマロでもね、こういう悩んでる子がこんなにたくさんいるんだと思って。
And from the Marshmallows, I saw how many people have these kinds of worries.
さ、1点だけ！ちょっと団長さ、脱毛のデメリット、
Now, just one thing! Hey Danchou, I forgot to mention
言うの忘れてた！
a drawback of hair removal!
ちょっとこれだけ伝えたい！全身脱毛による、の話なんだけど、
I just have to share this! It's about full-body hair removal...
うん、うん、うん。全身？
Yeah, yeah, yeah. Full-body?
毛があの、ないからさ、
Since there's no hair, you see...
あの、泡立たなくなった！ボディソープが！
The body soap stopped lathering!
え？ボディソープが？
Huh? The body soap?
え？そんなことある？！
Huh? Does that actually happen?!
え？そんなことある？
What? Does that happen?
えー？！
What?!
団長、今までさ、全身脱毛したことあるんだけど、
Danchou, you see, I've had full-body hair removal before,
で、でも昔はさ、学生の時とかはさ、
but back in the day, like when I was a student,
全然毛とかあったからさ、泡立ってたのよ、体が。
I had body hair, so my body would lather up.
だからその、わざわざこうゴシゴシする、なんていうの？
So I didn't need to specifically scrub with, what do you call it?
ボディソープを泡立てるさ、バスタオルみたいの、あるじゃん？
Like those bath towels you use to lather body soap, right?
あるじゃん。
Right.
ああいうのを使わなくてよかったんだけど、
I didn't have to use anything like that,
毛がなくなったら、
but once the hair was gone...
ツルツルで、もうなんかさ、泡立たせなきゃいけなくなった。
it was so slick that I had to manually lather it up!
毛で泡立ててたの？！
You were lathering with your hair?!
そんなわけ！
Of course not!
毛で泡立たないでしょ！
Hair doesn't make lather!
いや、泡立って... もしかしたらね、その...
No, it did lather... Or maybe, you know...
どんだけ生えてた？！
How much hair did you have?!
ボディソープの問題じゃないのか？
Isn't that just a problem with the body soap?
色々あるかもしれないけど、もしかしたらね、この脱毛考えてる人で、
There might be various reasons, but just in case someone considering hair removal
「自分も毛で泡立ってたわ」みたいな人がいたら、
is like, "Wait, I lather with my hair too,"
そこはデメリットになるから気をつけた方がいいかなっていうので、ちょっとそこだけね。
that could be a drawback, so you should be careful. I just wanted to mention that!
真剣な話かなって思ったけど、なんか「え？」ってなった。
I thought it was going to be serious, but then I was like, "Wait, what?"
そんなことあるんだ。
I had no idea that happens.
なるほどね。
Indeed.
え、でもあの、泡々になるさ、あの、なんて言うのあれ？
But you know those things that make tons of lather? What do you call them?
モシュモシュモシュってなってるやつ使ってんだけど、こより。
Koyori uses one of those squishy, puffy net things.
あの、泡を...
Like, for lathering...
あの、泡立てができるやつ？
The kind that foams it up?
あの、編み編みになってる、編み編みがふわふわふわって集まってるやつ。
The mesh ones, where the netting is all bunched up fluffy.
あー、あるあるある！
Ah, right, right, right!
あれ使えばもうさ、最初からぶわーって泡立って、そのまま滑らせればオッケーになる。
If you use that, it foams right up into a huge lather, and you just glide it over your skin.
そう。
Exactly.
ね、あれ、あれすごい。あれ革命よな。
Yeah, that thing is amazing. It's a revolution.
うん。
Yeah.
だからその、全身脱毛する人はそれを買って...
So anyone getting full-body hair removal should buy that...
あ、そう！泡立てネット
Ah, right! A foaming net.
買わないと泡立たない。
If you don't buy one, it won't lather.
泡立... ま、そ- そうなのかな？
Lather... Well, is- is that so?
まあまあまあ、そういう人もいるってことですね。
Well, well, I guess some people are like that.
いる。まあ、ちょっと個人差あると思いますけど。
Yeah. I think there are individual differences, though.
はい。泡立てネットおすすめなんでぜひ、
Yes. Foaming nets are recommended, so...
あの、男子諸君もね使っていただければ...
we'd love it if all you guys out there used one...
使ってください。
Please use it.
え、でも、うん、どうなんだろうね？その...
Wait, but, yeah, I wonder how that works? Like...
もちろん、スネ毛とかさ、そういうのは、うちら生えてなかったけど、
Of course, like shin hair and stuff, we don't have that, but...
男の人ってスネ毛とか、腕毛とか濃い人いるじゃん。
some guys have really thick shin hair or arm hair, right?
逆にね、毛がある人が使うと、毛がすごい絡まっちゃうかもしれないから...
On the contrary, if someone hairy uses it, it might get super tangled in their hair, so...
ああ、泡立てネットが？ / うん。
Ah, the foaming net? / Yeah.
毛が絡まることあんの？！
Can body hair really get tangled like that?!
え？泡立てネットに？
Huh? In a foaming net?
剛毛だと...？
If it's super coarse...?
剛毛で、こう、いっぱい生えてるとさ、
If you're super hairy and have a ton of it,
なんか想像したけど、こうやって... なんか、めっちゃつきそうだから...
I just imagined rubbing like this... it feels like it would totally get caught, so...
あれじゃない？その人は、あの、これからね、あの...
wouldn't it? Those people, from now on...
毛、毛で... 毛で泡立てて...
With hair... lather it up using their own hair...
「ねえよ！」って言われてるけど。
The chat is saying "No way!" though.
ない？嘘、ないか！
No? Really, no way?!
分からない、想像で話しちゃった。
I don't know, I just spoke from my imagination!
私、泡立てネットのね、あの、小さな穴の1つ1つに毛が入っちゃうくらい...
I thought the hair would poke into every single tiny hole of the net...
絡まっちゃうかなって...
and get tangled up...
ちょっとボーボーぐらいの毛だったら一回、やめてみ... お試しでね、
If you have really bushy hair, maybe hold off... Or rather, test it out first,
使ってみるといいかもしれないですね。
it might be good to give it a try.
そうですね、はい。
That's right, yes.
なるほど、なるほど。はい。
I see, I see. Yes.
楽しかった。 / お気遣いありがとうございます。
That was fun. / Thank you for your consideration!
ま、楽しんでもらえてよかったです。ありがとうございます。
Well, I'm glad you enjoyed it! Thank you so much!
じゃ、ラミたんは、今日はどうでしたか？
So, Lamy-tan, how was it for you today?
え、今日は二人の体を隅々まで洗えるってことが確定したので...
Well, today it was confirmed that I get to wash every inch of both your bodies...
確定？！
Confirmed?!
確定したので、あの、洗う順番とかね、
Since it's confirmed, like the order to wash in,
あの、何を使ったらいいのかと言うのを聞いておこうと思います。
and what products to use, I think I'll ask about those.
ありがとうございます。待って、それどうしよう... そう、あ、はい。
Thank you. Wait, what should we do about that... Ah, yes.
え？
Huh?
え、じゃ、こよは？こよは？
Wait, what about Koyo? What about Koyo?
あ、はい！えっと、こよりはちょっと今のラミたんので本当に洗われることがあるのだろうかと...
Ah, yes! Um, hearing Lamy-tan just now made me wonder if I'm really going to get washed...
ちょっと今、男子小学生の気分になっているんですけど。
and now I feel like an elementary school boy!
あるかもよ。 / 本当かもって、ちょっと今、緊張してしまっているんですけど。
It might happen. / I'm getting nervous thinking it might actually be real!
はい。でも、やっぱこのゲストがいると、またね、ラミこよとまた別の価値観だったりとか...
Yes. But having a guest really brings perspectives different from Lami-Koyo's...
こう、出てこない発想とかだったりが出てきて...
and ideas we wouldn't normally come up with...
ノエたんが、とにかく優しいし...
And Noe-tan is just so incredibly kind...
ねー、優しいね。
Right? So kind.
なんか、包容力...
She has such an embracing vibe...
ね！結局なんでも受け止めてくれそうだなっていうので...
Right! She feels like someone who would accept anything in the end...
なんか、より好きになってしまいました！
so it made me love her even more!
えー！いや、嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
いや、団長も本当さ、このガチトーク出たかったから、今回ゲストに出れて嬉しいんだけど...
Honestly, I really wanted to be on Gachi Talk, so I was super happy to be a guest...
確かにこよちゃんがね、冒頭で言ってた
Though like Koyo-chan said at the beginning,
「結構人をね、選んでしまうのではないか」みたいな言ってたけど...
about how "it might not be for everyone"...
え、でも、団長はね、本当に今後もこのガチトーク続いていって...
But I really hope Gachi Talk keeps going in the future...
まあ、このね、ラインがオッケーなホロメンとかも出てきて...
and more Holomen who are okay with this line of talk appear...
その、なんだろうな、価値観とか色々聞けたらな、嬉しいなと思っておりますので...
so we can hear all sorts of values and opinions. That'd make me so happy, so...
優しいなあ。 / 優しい！
You're so sweet. / So sweet!
ちなみに、もういつでもね、暇なんで、もし困ったら...
By the way, I'm always free, so if you ever need someone...
いつでも駆り出して、永遠にゲストとか...
feel free to call on me anytime as an eternal guest...
ありがたい！無限ゲストだ！
We'd love that! An infinite guest!
スノツノエルになる可能性がありますね、これ。
At this rate, it might become Su-No-Tsu-Noel!
なるね！お願いいたします、是非！
It really could! Please do, definitely!
嬉しい！
I'm so glad!
またね、やっぱり女子一人増えるとね、色んな価値観があるんだなと思って、今日もすごく楽しかったです。
Having one more girl on really showed how many different perspectives there are. Today was so much fun!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ありがとう！ / また是非ノエたんも遊びに来てください！
Thank you! / Please come hang out again anytime, Noe-tan!
はーい！遊びに行きまーす！
Okay! I'll come visit!
感想は #すのすの女子トーク でぜひハッシュタグで呟いてくれると嬉しいです。よろしくお願いします！
Please tweet your impressions with the hashtag #SuNoSuGirlsTalk! Thank you!
お願いしまーす！
Please do!
ということで、夜遅くまでありがとうございました！それでは、おつガチトークで行きますか？
And with that, thank you for staying up late with us! Shall we finish with "Otsu-Gachi Talk"?
はーい！ / 締めまーす！せーの！
Yes! / Let's wrap it up! Ready, set...
おつガチトーク！
Otsu-Gachi Talk!
おやすみなさーい！
Good night~!
見てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for watching!
また会いに来てね！
Come see me again, okay?